<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>The Son of Neptune</title>
  <id>urn:book:6b6d242b-9b8b-4d2a-9ac6-d8bc1290c563</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:21Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_386.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="The Son of Neptune" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_15_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Rick Riordan" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Son%20of%20Neptune%20%28386%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Son%20of%20Neptune%20%28386%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Son%20of%20Neptune%20%28386%29/The%20Son%20of%20Neptune%20-%20Rick%20Riordan.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Son%20of%20Neptune%20%28386%29/The%20Son%20of%20Neptune%20-%20Rick%20Riordan.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <author>
    <name>Rick Riordan</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_15_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2011-10-04T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Hyperion Book CH</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Azizex666" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Sports &amp; Recreation" />
  <category term="Fiction - Young Adult" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Monsters" />
  <category term="Camping &amp; Outdoor Activities" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Heroes of Olympus" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 2 in the Heroes of Olympus series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        <strong>Percy is confused.</strong>
        When he awoke after his
      long sleep, he didn’t know much more than his name. His
      brain-fuzz is lingering, even after the wolf Lupa told him he
      is a demigod and trained him to fight. Somehow Percy managed
      to make it to the camp for half-bloods, despite the fact that
      he had to continually kill monsters that, annoyingly, would
      not stay dead. But the camp doesn't ring any bells with him.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Hazel is supposed to be dead.</strong>
        When she lived
      before, she didn’t do a very good job of it. When the
      Voice took over her mother and commanded Hazel to use her
      “gift” for an evil purpose, Hazel couldn’t
      say no. Now, because of her mistake, the future of the world
      is at risk.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Frank is a klutz.</strong>
        His grandmother claims he
      is descended from ancient heroes and can be anything he wants
      to be, but he doesn’t see it. He doesn’t even
      know who his father is. He keeps hoping Apollo will claim
      him, because the only thing he is good at is
      archery—although not good enough to help the Fifth
      Cohort win at war games. His big and bulky physique makes him
      feel like a clumsy ox, especially in front of Hazel, his
      closest friend at camp. He trusts her
      completely—enough, even, to share the secret he holds
      close to his heart.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Beginning at the “other” camp for half-bloods
      and extending as far north as the land beyond the gods, this
      breathtaking second installment in the Heroes of Olympus
      series introduces new demigods, revives fearsome monsters,
      and features other remarkable creatures, all of whom are
      destined to play a part in the most important quest of all:
      the Prophecy of Seven.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong> </strong>
        <br />
      </p>
      <h3>Amazon.com Review</h3>
      <p>
        <strong>Amazon Best Books of the Month, October
      2011:</strong>
        From the Roman demigod camp to the prison of
      Death himself,
        <em>The Son of Neptune</em>
        reunites readers with old friends
      and introduces them to a whole new cast of characters. The
      Roman camp is a far cry from Camp Half-Blood, but it’s
      every bit as fascinating to explore. Our heroes battle up and
      down the West Coast with impossibly few days before disaster
      is unleashed, fighting new foes and finding new friends along
      the way. Some of the mysteries from
        <em>The Lost Hero</em>
        are solved, while others loom even
      larger. Rick Riordan is a master at balancing just the right
      amount of seriousness and levity in every situation, and his
      three teen narrators point out the strangeness of the
      iterations of ancient myths in the modern world with spot-on
      accuracy. With page-turning adventure, witty dialogue, and
      fun, fascinating characters, this second installment of the
      Heroes of Olympus series is a must-read for any fan of myths
      and fables.
        <em>--Malissa Kent</em>
        <br />
      </p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>Sure to become a classic</p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
