<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>A Betrayal in Winter</title>
  <id>urn:book:0f49f1fe-2c78-4796-93b3-aff3846db497</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:10Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_531.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="A Betrayal in Winter" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_31_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Daniel Abraham" />
  <link href="../../Daniel%20Abraham/A%20Betrayal%20in%20Winter%20%28531%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Daniel%20Abraham/A%20Betrayal%20in%20Winter%20%28531%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Daniel%20Abraham/A%20Betrayal%20in%20Winter%20%28531%29/A%20Betrayal%20in%20Winter%20-%20Daniel%20Abraham.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="465 KB" />
  <link href="../../Daniel%20Abraham/A%20Betrayal%20in%20Winter%20%28531%29/A%20Betrayal%20in%20Winter%20-%20Daniel%20Abraham.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="665 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Daniel Abraham</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_31_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2007-08-21T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Tor Books</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Long Price Quartet" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 2 in the Long Price Quartet series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>
        Set 15 years after the events of 2006's
        <em>A Shadow in Summer</em>
        , Abraham's clever second novel
      follows the tribulations of Otah Machi, the sixth son of the
      Khai Machi. On the demise of the Khai, one son must dispose
      of all other contenders in order to become the new ruler.
      Exiled years ago for refusing to become a magic-wielding
      poet, Otah made his home far from Machi, changed his name to
      Itani, worked as a laborer and never interfered in affairs of
      state, hoping to escape the kill-or-be-killed tradition. Now
      the old Khai's death approaches, and Otah's oldest brother,
      Biitrah, has been smothered in his sleep. Whispered
      rumor—which may have been started by the Galts, an
      empire desperate to destroy the house of Machi—puts the
      blame for the murder on Otah. He returns to Machi, grimly
      acknowledging that he must kill his brothers to save himself.
      Mystery, love triangles and struggles with magical creatures
      called andat make for a slow-starting but well-rounded story.
        <br />
        Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division
      of Reed Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
      </p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>Setting and characters in the second Long Price Quartet
      volume are different from those in A Shadow in Summer (2006).
      In Machi, the khai, or lord of the city, is
      dying. Tradition enjoins his sons to fight one another
      to the last man, who becomes khai. These sons are reluctant.
      When they start dying anyway, suspicion falls on Otah, who
      fled the court years ago and now, in a distant city, is
      feeling torn. He doesn't want to go home, but his father has
      ordered one of Otah's few known friends to get him back.
      Someone in the empire of the Galts is conspiring with someone
      in Machi to overthrow the latter's ruling house. The world
      Abraham has created, in which poets who control andats
      (magical beings composed of thought) constitute an elite in a
      once-great empire, remains fascinating, not least because
      there's more of the andats and more intrapolitical bickering
      here as well as a collection of characters who keep one
      turning pages. Murray, Frieda</p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
