<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Winter Warriors</title>
  <id>urn:book:21c4d6ee-ccef-4128-aee3-f17ee8bbe3ef</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:58Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_498.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Winter Warriors" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Winter%20Warriors%20%28498%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Winter%20Warriors%20%28498%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Winter%20Warriors%20%28498%29/Winter%20Warriors%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="419 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Winter%20Warriors%20%28498%29/Winter%20Warriors%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="562 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>1997-01-02T06:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Del Rey</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Fantasy fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy Fiction; American" />
  <category term="Demonology" />
  <category term="Prophecies" />
  <category term="Warriors" />
  <category term="American" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Drenai" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 8 in the Drenai series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        Winged demons gather, silent and unseen, above the city of
      Usa, their talons long and sharp. Their purpose is clear, as
      is the prophesy: Upon the deaths of the three kings, the
      demon riders of the Krayakin will become flesh, free to slake
      their thirst with human blood - and the stench of evil will
      cover the land.  
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Two of the kings are already dead. For the prophesy to be
      fulfilled, spreading carnage across the world, the Demon Lord
      must sacrifice the third king: Queen Axiana's unborn child.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>When Emperor Skanda disbands his army, the pregnant queen
      takes flight, pursued by the Lords of the Undead. All hope
      lies with three ancient heroes, though discarded by the
      emperor, they are still Drenai soldiers: Bison the giant,
      Kebra the bowman, and the great swordsman Nogusta - the Demon
      Lord's greatest foe. But will these warriors - once the best
      in the land - be enough to stem the tide of gruesome horror
      that threatens to envelop the world?</p>
      <h3>Amazon.com Review</h3>
      <p>David Gemmell has a talent for fantasy tales of heroism
      and villainy that feature characters who, while
      sympathetically flawed, are almost superhumanly good at what
      they do. Often these people are warriors: finely drawn,
      emotionally complex, and struggling with their individual
      human challenges against the backdrop of epic events.</p>
      <p>
        The heroic figures here are three Drenai soldiers,
      Nogusta, Bison, and Kebra, whose services have been rejected
      by their king because they are no longer young. However,
      while these old friends might be a tad past their best, they
      are still very good indeed, and when they are called upon to
      protect the infant heir to the throne, the little prince
      could not be in better hands. In the midst of flight and
      eventual, desperate battle against the forces of the demon
      lord Anharat, they fight not only a human army and a band of
      demon riders bent on the heir's death but their own doubts
      about their ability and worth. Gemmell is particularly deft
      at describing fine gradations of the friendship between the
      three men, including the subtleties of liking, of loving, and
      of the different strengths that come with age.
        <em>Winter Warriors</em>
        is both a fast-paced fantasy
      adventure and a powerful story of living and dying well.
        <em>--Luc Duplessis</em>
      </p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>
        "David Gemmell tells a tale of very real adventure, the
      stuff of true epic fantasy."
        <br />
        -R. A. SALVATORE
        <br />
           Author of the DemonWars trilogy
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
