<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Pathfinder</title>
  <id>urn:book:5550d57f-6d1b-466f-9f08-b9f62e739b10</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:33Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_419.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Pathfinder" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Pathfinder%20%28419%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Pathfinder%20%28419%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Pathfinder%20%28419%29/Pathfinder%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="475 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Pathfinder%20%28419%29/Pathfinder%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="723 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2010-11-23T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Simon Pulse</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Action &amp; Adventure" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Time Travel" />
  <category term="History" />
  <category term="Interplanetary Voyages" />
  <category term="Psychic ability" />
  <category term="Family" />
  <category term="Science &amp; Technology" />
  <category term="Young adult fiction" />
  <category term="Space colonies" />
  <category term="Identity" />
  <category term="Identity (Philosophical Concept)" />
  <category term="Young Adult Fiction; American" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Pathfinder" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Pathfinder series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <h3>From School Library Journal</h3>
      <p>Gr 7 Up–Card's latest work of speculative fiction
      twists together tropes of fantasy and science fiction into
      something fine indeed. Rigg and his father are trappers by
      trade, but Rigg has been instructed throughout his 13 years
      in languages, sciences, history, and politics. The teen is
      therefore somewhat mentally prepared for the quest that his
      father thrusts upon him with his dying breath–to go to
      the capital city and find his sister. Both Rigg and his
      friend, Umbo, have a special ability that aids
      them–Rigg can see the paths of all living things,
      regardless of intervening obstructions or even time, and Umbo
      can seemingly change the movement of time itself. Needless to
      say, the two meet various friends and foes and can't always
      tell which is which as they journey onward. Juxtaposed with
      this main story is an entirely different narrative, told in a
      page or two at the beginning of each chapter. This is the
      tale of Ram Odin, human pilot of a colony ship from Earth,
      traveling to a new world with the use of space-folding
      technology. The combination of science fiction and fantasy as
      well as a surprising revelation at the end harken back to
      genre classics like Robert Silverberg's Lord Valentine's
      Castle (HarperCollins, 1980) and Roger Zelazny's Nine Princes
      in Amber (Doubleday, 1970). This novel should appeal to
      Card's legion of fans as well as anyone who enjoys
      speculative fiction with characters who rely on quick
      thinking rather than violence or tales of mind-bending
      time-travel conundrums.–Eric Norton, McMillan Memorial
      Library, Wisconsin Rapids, WI. (c) Copyright 2010. Library
      Journals LLC, a wholly owned subsidiary of Media Source, Inc.
      No redistribution permitted.</p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>
        <em>Starred Review</em>
        The first in a series, Card’s
      latest title has much in common with his Ender Wiggins books:
      precocious teens with complementary special talents,
      callously manipulative government authorities, endlessly
      creative worlds, and Card’s refusal to dumb down a plot
      for a young audience. Here he takes the notions of folding
      space and time, embracing paradox, “adopting a rule set
      in which . . . causality . . . controls reality, regardless
      of where it occurs on the timeline.” Thirteen-year-old
      Rigg is a Pathfinder, one who sees the paths of others’
      pasts. Rigorously trained and thoroughly educated by his
      demanding father, Rigg is horrified when Father dies
      unexpectedly after a final order to find the sister he never
      knew he had. Rigg is accompanied on this journey by a small
      group of friends who have powers of bending and manipulating
      the flow of time. Card also skillfully twines a separate
      story line into the plot, featuring earth’s
      colonization of distant planets, led by the idealistic young
      pilot Ram Odin. Fast paced and thoroughly engrossing, the
      650-plus pages fly by, challenging readers to care about and
      grasp sophisticated, confusing, and captivating ideas. As in
      L’Engle’s Time Quartet, science is secondary to
      the human need to connect with others, but Card does not shy
      away from full and fascinating discussions of the paradoxical
      worlds he has created. Grades 8-12. --Debbie Carton
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
