<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>The Lost Hero</title>
  <id>urn:book:c9996958-808a-46e5-a422-bbdd344cf790</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:21Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_388.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="The Lost Hero" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_15_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Rick Riordan" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Lost%20Hero%20%28388%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Lost%20Hero%20%28388%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Lost%20Hero%20%28388%29/The%20Lost%20Hero%20-%20Rick%20Riordan.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Lost%20Hero%20%28388%29/The%20Lost%20Hero%20-%20Rick%20Riordan.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="936 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Rick Riordan</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_15_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2010-01-02T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Hyperion Book CH</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fables" />
  <category term="Legends" />
  <category term="Azizex666" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Myths" />
  <category term="Fiction - Young Adult" />
  <category term="Legends; Myths; Fables" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Heroes of Olympus" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Heroes of Olympus series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        <strong>Jason has a problem.</strong>
        He doesn’t
      remember anything before waking up on a school bus holding
      hands with a girl. Apparently she’s his girlfriend
      Piper, his best friend is a kid named Leo, and they’re
      all students in the Wilderness School, a boarding school for
      “bad kids.” What he did to end up here, Jason has
      no idea—except that everything seems very wrong.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Piper has a secret.</strong>
        Her father has been
      missing for three days, and her vivid nightmares reveal that
      he’s in terrible danger. Now her boyfriend
      doesn’t recognize her, and when a freak storm and
      strange creatures attack during a school field trip, she,
      Jason, and Leo are whisked away to someplace called Camp
      Half-Blood. What is going on?
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Leo has a way with tools.</strong>
        His new cabin at
      Camp Half-Blood is filled with them. Seriously, the place
      beats Wilderness School hands down, with its weapons
      training, monsters, and fine-looking girls. What’s
      troubling is the curse everyone keeps talking about, and that
      a camper’s gone missing. Weirdest of all, his bunkmates
      insist they are all—including Leo—related to a
        <em>god</em>
        . 
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Rick Riordan, the best-selling author of the Percy Jackson
      series, pumps up the action and suspense in
        <em>The Lost Hero</em>
        , the first book in The Heroes of
      Olympus series.  Fans of demi-gods, prophesies, and
      quests will be left breathless--and panting for Book Two.
      </p>
      <h3>From School Library Journal</h3>
      <p>Gr 5-9-This book will delight fans of The Lightning Thief
      (Hyperion, 2005) as Percy, Annabeth, and others play roles in
      the new prophecy and its subsequent quest. A few months after
      The Last Olympian (Hyperion, 2009) ends, Jason wakes up on a
      bus filled with problem kids from the Wilderness School who
      are headed to the Grand Canyon. He has no memory of his
      previous life, but seems to be with his girlfriend, Piper,
      and his best friend, Leo. The action takes off quickly: storm
      spirits attack them and capture their coach, who turns out to
      be a Satyr. Searching for Percy, who is missing, Annabeth
      arrives and takes the three to Camp Half-Blood, where they
      learn that they are demigods. Their parents are gods in their
      Roman rather than Greek personae. By sunset of the solstice
      in three days, the teens must rescue Hera, Queen of the gods,
      or Porphyrion, the giant king created to destroy Zeus and
      unseat the gods of Olympus, will rise. Their quest takes them
      across the United States, sometimes flying on a mechanical,
      60-foot dragon, as they use their power and wits against
      Medea, King Midas, and the giant cannibal Enceladus. Riordan
      excels at clever plot devices and at creating an urgent sense
      of cliff-hanging danger. His interjection of humor by
      incongruous juxtaposition-Medea, for example, heads up a New
      York City department store-provides some welcome relief. The
      young heroes deal with issues familiar to teens today: Who am
      I? Can I live up to the expectations of others? Having read
      the first series is helpful but not essential, and the
      complex plot is made for sequels.-Connie Tyrrell Burns,
      Mahoney Middle School, South Portland, ME (c) Copyright 2010.
      Library Journals LLC, a wholly owned subsidiary of Media
      Source, Inc. No redistribution permitted.</p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>Readers longing for a return to Camp Half-Blood will get
      their wish in the first novel of the Heroes of Olympus
      series, which follows Riordan’s popular Percy Jackson
      and the Olympians series and includes some of the same
      characters in minor roles. The new cast features Jason,
      Piper, and Leo, teen demigods who are just coming to
      understand and use their unique abilities as they learn how
      much depends upon their wits, courage, and fast-developing
      friendship. Setting up the books to come, the backstory of a
      master plan to unseat the gods is complex but is doled out in
      manageable bits with a general air of foreboding. Meanwhile,
      the action scenes come frequently as the three heroic teens
      fight monstrous enemies in North American locales, including
      the Grand Canyon, Quebec City, Detroit, Chicago, Omaha, Pikes
      Peak, and Sonoma Valley. Flashes of humor lighten the mood at
      times, but a tone of urgency and imminent danger seems as
      integral to this series as the last. With appealing new
      characters within a familiar framework, this spin-off will
      satisfy the demand for more. Grades 4-8. --Carolyn Phelan</p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
