<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Inkspell</title>
  <id>urn:book:cce0733d-3e97-4538-826b-94ec16b87d81</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:09Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_533.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Inkspell" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_32_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Cornelia Funke" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkspell%20%28533%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkspell%20%28533%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkspell%20%28533%29/Inkspell%20-%20Cornelia%20Funke.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="519 KB" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkspell%20%28533%29/Inkspell%20-%20Cornelia%20Funke.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="765 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Cornelia Funke</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_32_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2005-01-02T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Scholastic Inc.</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Characters in Literature" />
  <category term="Magic" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Books and Reading" />
  <category term="Characters and Characteristics in Literature" />
  <category term="Books &amp; Libraries" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Inkheart" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 2 in the Inkheart series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      The captivating sequel to INKHEART, the critically
    acclaimed, international bestseller by Cornelia
    Funke--available for the first time in a beautifully designed
    trade paperback!
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Although a year has passed, not a day goes by without Meggie
    thinking of INKHEART, the book whose characters became real.
    But for Dustfinger, the fire-eater brought into being from
    words, the need to return to the tale has become desperate.
    When he finds a crooked storyteller with the ability to read
    him back, Dustfinger leaves behind his young apprentice Farid
    and plunges into the medieval world of his past. Distraught,
    Farid goes in search of Meggie, and before long, both are
    caught inside the book, too. But the story is threatening to
    evolve in ways neither of them could ever have imagined.</p>
    <h3 xmlns="">Amazon.com Review</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Just a few chapters into
      <em>Inkspell</em>
      , Mo (a.k.a. "Silvertongue") sagely says to
    his daughter, "Stories never really end, Meggie, even if the
    books like to pretend they do. Stories always go on. They don't
    end on the last page, any more than they begin on the first
    page." A fitting meta-observation for this, the unplanned
    second installment in Cornelia Funke's beloved now-trilogy.
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Of course, it's that sort of earnest, almost gushing
    veneration of books and book-loving that made the absorbing
    suspense-fantasy
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      so wonderful in the first place, with that
    lit-affection getting woven integrally into the plot (
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      being both Funke's first book in the series,
    and the fictitious book within that book, authored by the
    frustrated Fenoglio, now trapped within the book, er, within
    the book. Fenoglio, perhaps not surprisingly,
    self-referentially wishes in
      <em>Inkspell</em>
      that he had written a sequel to
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      .)
      <em>Inkspell</em>
      should serve as a special treat for fans of
    the first book, as characters from
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      who have found themselves in the "real world"
    (if there is such a thing) find themselves read back into their
    own mythic, word-spun world--along with some of our favorite
    "real-world" characters. As with the previous book, Funke's
    greatest accomplishment here is telling such a rich and
    involving (and fun!) story, while still managing sweet, subtle
    commentary on the nature of words and meaning. Expect a
    tantalizing finale, too--as Funke says, "No reader will forgive
    me the ending, though, without a part three."
      <em>(Ages 8 and up) --Paul Hughes</em>
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From School Library Journal</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Grade 5 Up–This sequel begins a year after the
    conclusion of Funke's popular
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      (Scholastic, 2003). In this fantasy world,
    certain readers have the power to bring characters out of
    books–and send them back. Meggie and Farid, apprentices
    to the fire-eater Dustfinger, follow him to the Inkworld, the
    land of the book-within-a-book,
      <em>Inkheart,</em>
      after he has been read back into its story
    by a mysterious man named Orpheus. Orpheus uses his powers to
    read Mortola and Basta, some of the villains of the first
    volume, into the story, along with Meggie's parents. In
    Inkworld, Meggie enlists the help of Fenoglio, the original
    author of
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      , to help create a new future for her parents
    and herself as palace intrigues, war, and the Silver Prince
    threaten. The story moves along at a rapid pace, from Farid and
    Dustfinger's original meeting with Orpheus to Farid's warning
    of Mortola's return to the shift of action to the Inkworld and
    the heightening conflict in both worlds. Expanding on the ideas
    behind
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      , Funke explores what might happen if authors
    try to change the world they have created. Familiar characters
    and those new to this volume are clearly drawn. This is an
    involving story that will draw readers smoothly to its
    conclusion and leave them waiting for the final volume in this
    projected trilogy.–
      <em>Beth L. Meister, Pleasant View Elementary School, Franklin,
    WI</em>
      <br />
      Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division of Reed
    Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
    </p>
  </content>
</entry>
