<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows</title>
  <id>urn:book:b49c8d14-c88a-4046-a989-551d340cee38</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:46Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_453.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_24_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="J. K. Rowling" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Deathly%20Hallow%20%28453%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Deathly%20Hallow%20%28453%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Deathly%20Hallow%20%28453%29/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Deathly%20Ha%20-%20J.%20K.%20Rowling.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Deathly%20Hallow%20%28453%29/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Deathly%20Ha%20-%20J.%20K.%20Rowling.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <author>
    <name>J. K. Rowling</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_24_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>0101-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <category term="child_adv" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Harry Potter" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 7 in the Harry Potter series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Readers beware. The brilliant, breathtaking conclusion to
    J. K. Rowling’s spellbinding series is not for
    the faint of heart—such revelations, battles, and
    betrayals await in Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows that no
    fan will make it to the end unscathed. Luckily, Rowling has
    prepped loyal readers for the end of her series by doling out
    increasingly dark and dangerous tales of magic and mystery,
    shot through with lessons about honor and contempt, love and
    loss, and right and wrong. Fear not, you will find no spoilers
    in our review—to tell the plot would ruin the journey,
    and Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows is an odyssey the
    likes of which Rowling’s fans have not yet seen, and are
    not likely to forget. But we would be remiss if we did not
    offer one small suggestion before you embark on your final
    adventure with Harry—bring plenty of tissues. The heart
    of Book 7 is a hero’s mission—not just in
    Harry’s quest for the Horcruxes, but in his journey from
    boy to man—and Harry faces more danger than that found in
    all six books combined, from the direct threat of the Death
    Eaters and You-Know-Who, to the subtle perils of losing faith
    in himself. Attentive readers would do well to remember
    Dumbledore’s warning about making the choice between
    “what is right and what is easy,” and know that
    Rowling applies the same difficult principle to the conclusion
    of her series. While fans will find the answers to hotly
    speculated questions about Dumbledore, Snape, and You-Know-Who,
    it is a testament to Rowling’s skill as a storyteller
    that even the most astute and careful reader will be taken by
    surprise. A spectacular finish to a phenomenal series, Harry
    Potter and the Deathly Hallows is a bittersweet read for fans.
    The journey is hard, filled with events both tragic and
    triumphant, the battlefield littered with the bodies of the
    dearest and despised, but the final chapter is as brilliant and
    blinding as a phoenix’s flame, and fans and skeptics
    alike will emerge from the confines of the story with full but
    heavy hearts, giddy and grateful for the experience.</p>
  </content>
</entry>
