<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Elantris</title>
  <id>urn:book:513f4378-aab1-49d0-8f35-0a8180db9e0d</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:22Z</updated>
  <link href="./1a50779c%40book_563.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Elantris" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/4801887d%40author_3_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Brandon Sanderson" />
  <link href="../../Brandon%20Sanderson/Elantris%20%28563%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Brandon%20Sanderson/Elantris%20%28563%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Brandon%20Sanderson/Elantris%20%28563%29/Elantris%20-%20Brandon%20Sanderson.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="751 KB" />
  <link href="../../Brandon%20Sanderson/Elantris%20%28563%29/Elantris%20-%20Brandon%20Sanderson.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <author>
    <name>Brandon Sanderson</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/4801887d@author_3_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2005-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Tor Books</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Romance" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Adult" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        Elantris was the capital of Arelon: gigantic, beautiful,
      literally radiant, filled with benevolent beings who used
      their powerful magical abilities for the benefit of all. Yet
      each of these demigods was once an ordinary person until
      touched by the mysterious transforming power of the Shaod.
      Ten years ago, without warning, the magic failed. Elantrians
      became wizened, leper-like, powerless creatures, and Elantris
      itself dark, filthy, and crumbling.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Arelon's new capital, Kae, crouches in the shadow of
      Elantris. Princess Sarene of Teod arrives for a marriage of
      state with Crown Prince Raoden, hoping -- based on their
      correspondence -- to also find love. She finds instead that
      Raoden has died and she is considered his widow. Both Teod
      and Arelon are under threat as the last remaining holdouts
      against the imperial ambitions of the ruthless religious
      fanatics of Fjordell. So Sarene decides to use her new status
      to counter the machinations of Hrathen, a Fjordell high
      priest who has come to Kae to convert Arelon and claim it for
      his emperor and his god.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        But neither Sarene nor Hrathen suspect the truth about
      Prince Raoden. Stricken by the same curse that ruined
      Elantris, Raoden was secretly exiled by his father to the
      dark city. His struggle to help the wretches trapped there
      begins a series of events that will bring hope to Arelon, and
      perhaps reveal the secret of Elantris itself.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        A rare epic fantasy that doesn't recycle the classics and
      that is a complete and satisfying story in one volume,
      Elantris is fleet and fun, full of surprises and characters
      to care about. It's also the wonderful debut of a welcome new
      star in the constellation of fantasy.
        <br />
      </p>
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>
        Starred Review. Sanderson's outstanding fantasy debut,
      refreshingly complete unto itself and free of the usual genre
      clichés, offers something for everyone: mystery, magic,
      romance, political wrangling, religious conflict, fights for
      equality, sharp writing and wonderful, robust characters. The
      godlike inhabitants of Elantris, once the capital of the land
      of Arelon, have degenerated into powerless, tortured souls,
      unable to die, after the city's magic inexplicably broke 10
      years earlier. When the same curse strikes Prince Raoden of
      Arelon and he's imprisoned in Elantris, he refuses to
      surrender to his grim fate and instead strives to create a
      society out of the fallen and to unlock the secret that will
      restore the city's glory. Meanwhile, Princess Sarene of Kae
      (Arelon's new capital), who was betrothed to Raoden sight
      unseen, believes her intended has died. Officially declared
      his widow, she must use her political savvy and wit to
      protect Kae from malevolent forces without and within the
      city, chiefly Hrathen, a leader of the creepy Shu-Dereth
      faith, who aims to either convert Kae or destroy it within
      three months. The intrigue and excitement grow steadily in
      this smoothly written, perfectly balanced narrative; by the
      end readers won't want to put it down. As the blurb from
      Orson Scott Card suggests, Sanderson is a writer to watch.
        <br />
        Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division
      of Reed Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
      </p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>
        Until 10 years ago, Elantris was the capital of Arelon,
      inhabited by ordinary humans transformed into magic-using
      demigods by the Shaod. But the magic failed, Elantris started
      to rot, and its inhabitants turned into powerless wrecks.
      Princess Sarene of Teod arrives in Kae, the new capital,
      close enough to Elantris to constantly remind of faded glory,
      prepared for a marriage to ally Teod and Arelon against the
      religious imperialists of Fjordell. But, she is told, her
      fiance, Prince Raoden, is dead. She and a recently arrived
      high priest of Fjordell, Hrathen, clash. Sarene tries to
      retain the freedom of Teod and Arelon, Hrathen tries to
      incite the populace to convert so that Fjordell can take
      over. Neither suspects the truth about Raoden. Taken by the
      Shaod, he struggles to unite the crippled Elantrians and
      discover why the magic failed. The unrest comes to a head as
      governments topple, the Elantrians' secrets are revealed, and
      Fjordell's forces arrive. A surprisingly satisfying,
      single-volume epic fantasy that invokes a complex, vibrant
      world.
        <em>Regina Schroeder</em>
        <br />
        <em>Copyright © American Library Association. All rights
      reserved</em>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
