<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</title>
  <id>urn:book:23bcaa2b-a9b5-4dd2-93bc-110aa125c6f2</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:44Z</updated>
  <link href="./40d5bae7%40book_456.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/c4512670%40author_24_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="J. K. Rowling" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Goblet%20of%20Fire%20%28456%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Goblet%20of%20Fire%20%28456%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Goblet%20of%20Fire%20%28456%29/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Goblet%20of%20-%20J.%20K.%20Rowling.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="660 KB" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Goblet%20of%20Fire%20%28456%29/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Goblet%20of%20-%20J.%20K.%20Rowling.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="902 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>J. K. Rowling</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/c4512670@author_24_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2000-11-15T09:32:56Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Scholastic</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="People &amp; Places" />
  <category term="Science Fiction; Fantasy; Magic" />
  <category term="Children's Books" />
  <category term="Children: Grades 4-6" />
  <category term="Ages 9-12 Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction; Fantasy; &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Friendship" />
  <category term="Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry (Imaginary place)" />
  <category term="Potter; Harry (Fictitious character)" />
  <category term="Wizards" />
  <category term="Magic" />
  <category term="Europe" />
  <category term="Schools" />
  <category term="Humorous Stories" />
  <category term="School &amp; Education" />
  <category term="England" />
  <category term="Hogwarts School of Witchcraft" />
  <category term="Orphans" />
  <category term="Fantasy Fiction; English" />
  <category term="Children's Literature" />
  <category term="Determination (Personality trait)" />
  <category term="Witches" />
  <category term="Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry (Imaginary organization)" />
  <category term="Body; Mind &amp; Spirit" />
  <category term="Magick Studies" />
  <category term="Teenagers and death" />
  <category term="Children's 9-12 - Fiction - Fantasy" />
  <category term="Harry (Fictitious character)" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Body" />
  <category term="Fantasy fiction" />
  <category term="Mind &amp; Spirit" />
  <category term="English" />
  <category term="&amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Potter" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Harry Potter" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 4 in the Harry Potter series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">Amazon.com Review</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      In
      <em>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</em>
      , J.K. Rowling
    offers up equal parts danger and delight--and any number of
    dragons, house-elves, and death-defying challenges. Now 14, her
    orphan hero has only two more weeks with his Muggle relatives
    before returning to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
    Yet one night a vision harrowing enough to make his
    lightning-bolt-shaped scar burn has Harry on edge and
    contacting his godfather-in-hiding, Sirius Black. Happily, the
    prospect of attending the season's premier sporting event, the
    Quidditch World Cup, is enough to make Harry momentarily forget
    that Lord Voldemort and his sinister familiars--the Death
    Eaters--are out for murder.
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Readers, we will cast a giant invisibility cloak over any
    more plot and reveal only that You-Know-Who is very much after
    Harry and that this year there will be no Quidditch matches
    between Gryffindor, Ravenclaw, Hufflepuff, and Slytherin.
    Instead, Hogwarts will vie with two other magicians' schools,
    the stylish Beauxbatons and the icy Durmstrang, in a Triwizard
    Tournament. Those chosen to compete will undergo three supreme
    tests. Could Harry be one of the lucky contenders?</p>
    <p xmlns="">But Quidditch buffs need not go into mourning: we get our
    share of this great game at the World Cup. Attempting to go
    incognito as Muggles, 100,000 witches and wizards converge on a
    "nice deserted moor." As ever, Rowling magicks up the details
    that make her world so vivid, and so comic. Several spectators'
    tents, for instance, are entirely unquotidian. One is a
    minipalace, complete with live peacocks; another has three
    floors and multiple turrets. And the sports paraphernalia on
    offer includes rosettes "squealing the names of the players" as
    well as "tiny models of Firebolts that really flew, and
    collectible figures of famous players, which strolled across
    the palm of your hand, preening themselves." Needless to say,
    the two teams are decidedly different, down to their mascots.
    Bulgaria is supported by the beautiful veela, who instantly
    enchant everyone--including Ireland's supporters--over to their
    side. Until, that is, thousands of tiny cheerleaders engage in
    some pyrotechnics of their own: "The leprechauns had risen into
    the air again, and this time, they formed a giant hand, which
    was making a very rude sign indeed at the veela across the
    field."</p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Long before her fourth installment appeared, Rowling warned
    that it would be darker, and it's true that every exhilaration
    is equaled by a moment that has us fearing for Harry's life,
    the book's emotions running as deep as its dangers. Along the
    way, though, she conjures up such new characters as Alastor
    "Mad-Eye" Moody, a Dark Wizard catcher who may or may not be
    getting paranoid in his old age, and Rita Skeeter, who beetles
    around Hogwarts in search of stories. (This
      <em>Daily Prophet</em>
      scoop artist has a Quick-Quotes Quill
    that turns even the most innocent assertion into tabloid
    innuendo.) And at her bedazzling close, Rowling leaves several
    plot strands open, awaiting book 5. This fan is ready to wager
    that the author herself is part veela--her pen her wand, her
    commitment to her world complete. (Ages 9 and older)
      <em>--Kerry Fried</em>
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From Publishers Weekly</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Even without the unprecedented media attention and
    popularity her magical series has attracted, it would seem too
    much to hope that Rowling could sustain the brilliance and wit
    of her first three novels. Astonishingly, Rowling seems to have
    the spell-casting powers she assigns her characters: this
    fourth volume might be her most thrilling yet. The novel opens
    as a confused Muggle overhears Lord Voldemort and his henchman,
    Wormtail (the escapee from book three, Azkaban) discussing a
    murder and plotting more deaths (and invoking Harry Potter's
    name); clues suggest that Voldemort and Wormtail's location
    will prove highly significant. From here it takes a while
    (perhaps slightly too long a while) for Harry and his friends
    to get back to the Hogwarts school, where Rowling is on surest
    footing. Headmaster Dumbledore appalls everyone by declaring
    that Quidditch competition has been canceled for the year; then
    he makes the exciting announcement that the Triwizard
    Tournament is to be held after a cessation of many hundred
    years (it was discontinued, he explains, because the death toll
    mounted so high). One representative from each of the three
    largest wizardry schools of Europe (sinister Durmstrang,
    luxurious Beauxbatons and Hogwarts) are to be chosen by the
    Goblet of Fire; because of the mortal dangers, Dumbledore casts
    a spell that allows only students who are at least 17 to drop
    their names into the Goblet. Thus no one foresees that the
    Goblet will announce a fourth candidate: Harry. Who has put his
    name into the Goblet, and how is his participation in the
    tournament linked, as it surely must be, to Voldemort's newest
    plot? The details are as ingenious and original as ever, and
    somehow (for catching readers off-guard must certainly get more
    difficult with each successive volume) Rowling plants the red
    herrings, the artful clues and tricky surprises that disarm the
    most attentive audience. A climax even more spectacular than
    that of Azkaban will leave readers breathless. The
    muscle-building heft of this volume notwithstanding, the clamor
    for book five will begin as soon as readers finish installment
    four. All ages. (July)
      <br />
      Copyright 2000 Reed Business Information, Inc.
    </p>
  </content>
</entry>
