<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Furies of Calderon</title>
  <id>urn:book:8c9aab47-f644-4483-a855-2f58264ed6b7</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:43Z</updated>
  <link href="./47b87efe%40book_452.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Furies of Calderon" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/5a35b3d3%40author_23_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Jim Butcher" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Furies%20of%20Calderon%20%28452%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Furies%20of%20Calderon%20%28452%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Furies%20of%20Calderon%20%28452%29/Furies%20of%20Calderon%20-%20Jim%20Butcher.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="625 KB" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Furies%20of%20Calderon%20%28452%29/Furies%20of%20Calderon%20-%20Jim%20Butcher.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="860 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Jim Butcher</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/5a35b3d3@author_23_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2004-01-01T05:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Ace</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Adventure" />
  <category term="Adult" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Codex Alera" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Codex Alera series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>For a thousand years, the people of Alera have united
      against the aggressive and threatening races that inhabit the
      world, using their unique bond with the furies - elementals
      of earth, air, fire, water, and metal. But now, Gaius Sextus,
      First Lord of Alera, grows old and lacks an heir. Ambitious
      High Lords plot and maneuver to place their Houses in
      positions of power, and a war of succession looms on the
      horizon." "Far from city politics in the Calderon Valley, the
      boy Tavi struggles with his lack of furycrafting. At fifteen,
      he has no wind fury to help him fly, no fire fury to light
      his lamps. Yet as the Alerans' most savage enemy - the Marat
      - return to the Valley, he will discover that his destiny is
      much greater than he could ever imagine." Caught in a storm
      of deadly wind furies, Tavi saves the life of a runaway slave
      named Amara. But she is actually a spy for Gaius Sextus, sent
      to the Valley to gather intelligence on traitors to the
      Crown, who may be in league with the barbaric Marat horde.
      And when the Valley erupts in chaos - when rebels war with
      loyalists and furies clash with furies - Amara will find
      Tavi's courage and resourcefulness to be a power greater than
      any fury - one that could turn the tides of war.</p>
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>
        At the start of Butcher's absorbing fantasy, the first in
      a new series, the barbarians are at the gates of the land of
      Alera, which has a distinct flavor of the Roman Empire (its
      ruler is named Quintus Sextus and its soldiers are organized
      in legions). Fortunately, Alera has magical defenses,
      involving the furies or elementals of water, earth, air, fire
      and metal, that protect against foes both internal and
      external. Amara, a young female spy, and her companion,
      Odiana, go into some of the land's remoter territories to
      discover if military commander Atticus Quentin is a
      traitor—another classic trope from ancient Rome. She
      encounters a troubled young man, Tavi, who has hitherto been
      concerned mostly with the vividly depicted predatory
      "herdbanes" that threaten his sheep as well as with his
      adolescent sexual urges (handled tastefully). Thinking that
      Amara is an escaping slave, Tavi decides to help her and is
      immediately sucked in over his head into a morass of
      intrigues, military, magical and otherwise. Butcher (
        <em>Storm Front</em>
        , etc.) does a thorough job of world
      building, to say nothing of developing his action scenes with
      an abundance of convincing detail. This page-turner bodes
      well for future volumes.
        <br />
        Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division
      of Reed Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
      </p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>
        This first book of a series, the Codex Aliera, is a real
      page-turner, with the classic plot of a kingdom threatened by
      both an outside invader and internal treachery enlivened by
      an abundance of original details and sheer storytelling
      gusto. For centuries, the ability of the people of Aliera to
      bond with furies--elemental spirits of earth, air, fire,
      water, and metal--has allowed them to defend their land
      against invaders. But the current lord is old and lacks an
      heir. So Aliera's traditional enemies plot with treacherous
      lords within the country to seize power. Far off in the
      mountains, the young lad Tavi struggles with his inability to
      attract and bond with a fury--and with sensual adolescent
      urges. He saves the life of a young girl he believes to be a
      slave, but who is actually an agent of the king, looking for
      traitors. Tavi is himself drawn into battle and war before he
      can say "lost sheep." A promising series launcher.
        <em>Frieda Murray</em>
        <br />
        <em>Copyright © American Library Association. All rights
      reserved</em>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
