<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Ghost King</title>
  <id>urn:book:697b3474-8558-4610-be4e-621085d5e077</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:53Z</updated>
  <link href="./6b1f5109%40book_481.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Ghost King" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/cde76a5b%40author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Ghost%20King%20%28481%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Ghost%20King%20%28481%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Ghost%20King%20%28481%29/Ghost%20King%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="351 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Ghost%20King%20%28481%29/Ghost%20King%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="468 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/cde76a5b@author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>1988-01-02T06:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Del Rey</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Stones of Power" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Stones of Power series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        Chaos and terror stalked the realm. The king had been
      slain by traitors, and the sword of power had been lost
      beyond the Circle of Mist. Armies of Saxons, Angles, Jutes,
      and Brigantes cut a gory swath across the land, led by
      puppets of the ruthless Witch Queen--whose minions included
      dark, bloodthirsty creatures and a savage, undead warrior.
        <br />
        All hope lay with young Thuro--in whose veins flowed
      the blood of kings. He would have to defeat the Witch Queen's
      monsters and travel to the land of the Mist, there to seek a
      ghostly army. And the only one who could prepare Thuro to
      achieve his birthright was the mountain warrior Culain, the
      one man who knew the queen's deadly secret . . .
        <br />
        The legend of the mystic Stones of Power begins with a
      tale of blood and glory, of love and betrayal, as a boy must
      come of age amidst the seemingly impossible quest to become
      the High King.
      </p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>'David Gemmell is several rungs above the good - right
      into the fabulous' Anne McCaffrey</p>
      <h3>From the Publisher</h3>
      <p>
        David Gemmell is so committed to his work that he's
      offered to leap naked out of an airplane if it would appeal
      to readers. We haven't taken him up on the offer. However,
      David has also acknowledged that three of his major
      influences were Louis Lamour, J.R.R. Tolkien, and Stan Lee.
      Tolkien wrote back, Lamour passed away before David had any
      opportunity to contact him, and Stan Lee lived thousands of
      miles away from David's British home. One out of three wasn't
      bad, but it could be improved upon.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        We were at the San Diego ComicCon, rustling up new
      readers, and David had just finished a two-hour continuous
      signing. A friend of mine spotted a familiar face, so I
      excused myself and darted away, returning a few moments later
      to say, "David Gemmell, I'd like you to meet Stan Lee." A
      tall, ruddy, and normally poised individual, David was struck
      speechless. Here was the man who, through his Marvel Comics
      stories, had reinvented the relationship between heroes and
      villains, forever blurring the barriers between good and
      evil. Before long the two fantasists were chatting away
      happily. Stan's wife, Joan, being British, was especially
      gracious to the London-born Gemmell. And Stan quickly
      demanded an autographed copy of LEGEND.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        David's a dynamic storyteller. His lands live and breathe.
      His heroes are mighty swordsmen, ax-wielders, and
      post-apocalyptic adventurers. In their prime they were the
      best in the business, but in David's tales, they've often
      passed their prime, so all they really want is peace and
      quiet. But life (and the author) aren't that kind, and these
      heroes are forced out of retirement, forced to face bloody
      hordes of the undead, armies from Hell. Worse, his heroes are
      generally saddled with young, green heroes. (Nothing drives
      you crazy more than a cocky kid.) But they overcome, and the
      cocky kids become heroes, too. This is great reading.
        <br />
                                                                                --Steve
      Saffel, Senior Editor
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
