<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Lord of the Silver Bow</title>
  <id>urn:book:28cce95d-3385-4388-9ec7-e5a9b0f69e0a</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:51Z</updated>
  <link href="./72e3d865%40book_476.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Lord of the Silver Bow" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/cde76a5b%40author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Lord%20of%20the%20Silver%20Bow%20%28476%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Lord%20of%20the%20Silver%20Bow%20%28476%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Lord%20of%20the%20Silver%20Bow%20%28476%29/Lord%20of%20the%20Silver%20Bow%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="474 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Lord%20of%20the%20Silver%20Bow%20%28476%29/Lord%20of%20the%20Silver%20Bow%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="673 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/cde76a5b@author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2005-09-19T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Ballantine Books</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Turkey" />
  <category term="War stories" />
  <category term="Greeks" />
  <category term="War &amp; Military" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Fantasy - Epic" />
  <category term="Trojan War" />
  <category term="Historical fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy - Historical" />
  <category term="Fiction - Fantasy" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Greeks - Turkey" />
  <category term="Historical" />
  <category term="Troy (Extinct city)" />
  <category term="Fantasy fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Historical - General" />
  <category term="American Historical Fiction" />
  <category term="Young Adult" />
  <category term="Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy" />
  <category term="Feuds" />
  <category term="Hector (Legendary character)" />
  <category term="War" />
  <category term="Sailors" />
  <category term="Revenge" />
  <category term="Women priests" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Adventure" />
  <category term="Historical fantasy fiction" />
  <category term="Andromache (Legendary character)" />
  <category term="Ship captains" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Troy" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Troy series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      He is a man of many names. Some call him the Golden One;
    others, the Lord of the Silver Bow. To the Dardanians, he is
    Prince Aeneas. But to his friends, he is Helikaon. Strong,
    fast, quick of mind, he is a bold warrior, hated by his
    enemies, feared even by his Trojan allies. For there is a
    darkness at the heart of the Golden One, a savagery that, once
    awakened, can be appeased only with blood.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Argurios the Mykene is a peerless fighter, a man of
    unbending principles and unbreakable will. Like all of the
    Mykene warriors, he lives to conquer and to kill. Dispatched by
    King Agamemnon to scout the defenses of the golden city of
    Troy, he is Helikaon’s sworn enemy.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Andromache is a priestess of Thera betrothed against her
    will to Hektor, prince of Troy. Scornful of tradition, skilled
    in the arts of war, and passionate in the ways of her order,
    Andromache vows to love whom she pleases and to live as she
    desires.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Now fate is about to thrust these three together–and,
    from the sparks of passionate love and hate, ignite a fire that
    will engulf the world.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Readers who know the works of David Gemmell expect nothing
    less than excellence from this author, whose taut prose,
    driving plots, and full-bodied characters have won him legions
    of fans the world over. Now, with this first masterly volume in
    an epic reimagining of the Trojan War, Gemmell has written an
    ageless drama of brave deeds and fierce battles, of honor and
    treachery, of love won and lost.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      <em>From the Hardcover edition.</em>
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From Publishers Weekly</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Starred Review. Bestseller Gemmell (
      <em>Legend</em>
      ) boldly recasts the Trojan War in this first of
    a new trilogy, which centers on a warrior variously called
    Helikaon, Aeneas or the Golden One, who's blessed by luck to
    have all he turns his hand to prosper. Populated by compelling
    and finely drawn characters taken from either Greek mythology
    (Odysseus, Hektor, etc.) or the author's own fertile
    imagination, the novel lays the groundwork for the war to come.
    Spurred by prophecy, Agamemnon, King of Mykene, sets his men
    the task of killing Aeneas. The ensuing conflict threatens to
    engulf the Mediterranean. While this enchanting tale is more
    historical fiction than fantasy (the obligatory oracles and
    Kassandra's prophecies are the only hints of magic), genre fans
    and more general readers alike will have trouble putting it
    down.
      <br />
      Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division of Reed
    Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From Booklist</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      This hefty historical fantasy opens a trilogy dealing with
    the Trojan War but without the usual number of variations on
    the theme readers have come to expect from prolific and popular
    fantasist Gemmell. The title character is Aeneas, not outwardly
    the Trojan hero, however, but a Trojan ally using the name
    Helikaon. He and the Greek Odysseus are on terms of mutual
    respect, and he is also in love with Andromache, the betrothed
    of Hector, Troy's greatest warrior. When relations between Troy
    and Mycenae start deteriorating dramatically, Helikaon/Aeneas
    is in several kinds of dilemma. We soon learn that Gemmell's
    isn't the Homeric scenario of the
      <em>Iliad,</em>
      however, because this book's Hector doesn't
    survive the battles of this preliminary book, and those occur
    before Agamemnon sets sail for Troy. Gemmell is a master of
    fast pacing and original, not to say offbeat, takes on
    legendary and mythical characters. The alternate
      <em>Iliad</em>
      he launches here does honor to his reputation
    and promises to lift it higher while adding notably to readers'
    pleasure.
      <em>Roland Green</em>
      <br />
      <em>Copyright © American Library Association. All rights
    reserved</em>
    </p>
  </content>
</entry>
