<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Hero in the Shadows</title>
  <id>urn:book:7b081f40-ffbb-41e6-b5c4-a90fc19c7636</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:57Z</updated>
  <link href="./7569a451%40book_495.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Hero in the Shadows" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/cde76a5b%40author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Hero%20in%20the%20Shadows%20%28495%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Hero%20in%20the%20Shadows%20%28495%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Hero%20in%20the%20Shadows%20%28495%29/Hero%20in%20the%20Shadows%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="402 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Hero%20in%20the%20Shadows%20%28495%29/Hero%20in%20the%20Shadows%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="589 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/cde76a5b@author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2000-10-03T05:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Del Rey</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Fantasy fiction" />
  <category term="Magic" />
  <category term="English Fiction" />
  <category term="Waylander (Fictitious Character)" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Drenai" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 9 in the Drenai series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        The ruined city of Kuan Hador reeks of dark mystery.
      Shunned by brigands and merchants alike, it is home to
      fearsome wild things and legends that freeze the blood--tales
      that speak of slavering white beasts, locked behind a
      powerful wall of spells, who possess an insatiable appetite
      for death. Millennia have passed since they were bound, and
      the spell of imprisonment has begun to fade. Soon the foul
      minions will be free to wreak a horrible vengeance against
      all that lives.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>But no army waits to oppose them, only a ragtag group of
      unlikely heroes. Leading them is the mysterious Gray Man, an
      enigmatic figure with a blood-drenched past who has killed
      for principle and for payment--a man of destiny known
      throughout the lands of the Drenai as Waylander the Slayer .
      . .</p>
      <h3>Amazon.com Review</h3>
      <p>
        In
        <em>Hero in the Shadows</em>
        , Waylander, the assassin hero of
      some of Gemmell's earlier books, is now a middle-aged man
      looking for peace in a world that will, for the most part,
      let him alone. The crimes of his past come back to haunt him,
      as he finds himself responsible for a young prince whose
      grandfather he murdered, and as creatures of doomed legend
      come back to rule the world with blood and horror. An aging
      paladin, a loud-mouthed braggart whom a magic sword has
      chosen, and a kitchen girl who is unusually handy with her
      knives become his allies, along with a priestess who is not
      telling all she knows, or all she is.
      </p>
      <p>
        Gemmell is one of the best writers of fantasy
      adventure--this new book is attractively gloomy in its
      atmosphere and has a pervading sense of the ironic. The
      action sequences are powerful and well visualized; Gemmell
      always knows how a particular sort of fight would feel. And
      there are no simple morals here--most of the characters,
      heroic or villainous, exist in the gray hinterland between
      dark and light, where evil acts are often performed in sorrow
      and good actions often have mixed motives behind them.
        <em>--Roz Kaveney, Amazon.co.uk</em>
      </p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>
        "Everything a fan of heroic fantasy could desire."
        <br />
        --STEPHEN DONALDSON
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "I am truly amazed at David Gemmell's ability to focus his
      writer's eye. His images are crisp and complete, a history
      lesson woven within the detailed tapestry of the highest
      adventure. Gemmell's characters are no less complete, real
      men and women with qualities good and bad, placed in trying
      times and rising to heroism or falling victim to their own
      weaknesses."
        <br />
        --R. A. SALVATORE
        <br />
           Author of Mortalis
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Gemmell is very talented; his characters are vivid and
      very convincingly realistic."
        <br />
        --CHRISTOPHER STASHEFF
        <br />
           Author of the Wizard of Rhyme novels
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
