<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Inkdeath</title>
  <id>urn:book:7eaa66d2-d7cf-4eb9-b63a-4965d9c90c0d</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:09Z</updated>
  <link href="./8e4426ec%40book_535.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Inkdeath" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/3429b204%40author_32_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Cornelia Funke" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkdeath%20%28535%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkdeath%20%28535%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkdeath%20%28535%29/Inkdeath%20-%20Cornelia%20Funke.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="539 KB" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkdeath%20%28535%29/Inkdeath%20-%20Cornelia%20Funke.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="726 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Cornelia Funke</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/3429b204@author_32_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2007-09-28T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Scholastic Inc.</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Characters in Literature" />
  <category term="Magic" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Books and Reading" />
  <category term="Law &amp; Crime" />
  <category term="Characters and Characteristics in Literature" />
  <category term="Kidnapping" />
  <category term="Childrens" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Books &amp; Libraries" />
  <category term="Bookbinding" />
  <category term="Romance" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Literary Criticism" />
  <category term="Adventure" />
  <category term="Crafts &amp; Hobbies" />
  <category term="Young Adult" />
  <category term="Book Printing &amp; Binding" />
  <category term="Children's Literature" />
  <category term="_nocatalog" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Inkheart" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 3 in the Inkheart series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      The masterful conclusion to the epic, award-winning, NYT
    bestselling INKHEART trilogy by internationally acclaimed
    author Cornelia Funke.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">The Adderhead--his immortality bound in a book by Meggie's
    father, Mo--has ordered his henchmen to plunder the villages.
    The peasants' only defense is a band of outlaws led by the
    Bluejay--Mo's fictitious double, whose identity he has
    reluctantly adopted. But the Book of Immortality is unraveling,
    and the Adderhead again fears the White Women of Death. To
    bring the renegade Bluejay back to repair the book, the
    Adderhead kidnaps all the children in the kingdom, dooming them
    to slavery in his silver mines unless Mo surrenders. First
    Dustfinger, now Mo: Can anyone save this cursed story?</p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From Publishers Weekly</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      This concluding volume in Funke's bestselling trilogy picks
    up where
      <em>Inkspell</em>
      left off, but sputters for a hundred pages
    filling in backstory. (Even then, an addendum is needed to
    identify a cast of 114 characters.) The Inkworld, full of dark
    magic, is under siege; the savagery of the Adderhead and his
    minions now extends to taking all the peasants' children until
    somebody delivers, as ransom, the Bluejay, a Robin
    Hood–style character whose identity has been assumed by
    Mo, Meggie's father (it was Mo who started all the trouble by
    reading several villains right out of the book-within-a-book,
      <em>Inkheart—</em>
      don't even consider reading this series
    out of order). The
      <em>Inkheart</em>
      author, Fenoglio, now living in Inkworld
    himself, has turned to drink; the odious Orpheus, when he's not
    under a maid's skirt, rewrites Fenoglio's work (editors!) to
    benefit himself. The interesting metafictional
    questions—can we alter destiny? shape our own
    fate?—are overwhelmed by the breakneck action, yet the
    villains aren't fully realized. More disappointingly, the
    formerly feisty Meggie, barely into her teens, has little to do
    but choose between two suitors. Funke seems to have forgotten
    her original installment was published for children. Ages
    9–up.
      <em>(Oct.)</em>
      <br />
      Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division of Reed
    Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From School Library Journal</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Grade 5–9—This final volume in the trilogy
    returns readers to Inkworld and its wide cast of characters.
    Under the rule of the evil Adderhead, it is a bleak and
    dangerous place. General gloominess bogs down the pace
    initially, as several characters agonize, sometimes tiresomely,
    over past regrets and the dire uncertainty of the future.
    Meggie, despite her gift of magical reading, remains a
    disappointingly dull protagonist, but other characters are
    quite compelling. Her bookbinding father, for instance, emerges
    as a swashbuckling outlaw, and, when he brings the fire-dancer
    Dustfinger back from the dead, things get really interesting.
    The assortment of villains is vivid and frightening, especially
    Mortola, who can change shape, and the immortal Adderhead. Even
    more intriguing is Mo, who evolves into a powerful and complex
    scoundrel as he explores the evil potential of his unique
    ability to make up stories, then read them into reality. The
    finale includes a thoroughly engrossing climax as the Adderhead
    and Mo meet their doom, though a subplot involving Meggie and
    her companions is less exciting. Despite occasional weaknesses
    in plotting and characterization, Funke successfully explores
    ideas of fate, free will, and the power of story in a
    multilayered tale with many dramatic moments, bringing the
    series to a satisfying conclusion. Summaries of the first two
    books and a list of names and places are provided for those new
    to the series, but this last installment will be appreciated
    most by readers who start with the first title.—
      <em>Steven Engelfried, Multnomah County Library, OR</em>
      <br />
      Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division of Reed
    Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
    </p>
  </content>
</entry>
