<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Xenocide</title>
  <id>urn:book:1749019a-ab3c-443f-9794-f7663d1d5def</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:34Z</updated>
  <link href="./8f9e839%40book_422.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Xenocide" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/91cd090e%40author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Xenocide%20%28422%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Xenocide%20%28422%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Xenocide%20%28422%29/Xenocide%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="487 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Xenocide%20%28422%29/Xenocide%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="738 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/91cd090e@author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2010-01-31T07:30:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Tandem Library</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Fiction - Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction - General" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Ender Saga" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 3 in the Ender Saga series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Xenocide The millennia-long saga of Andrew Wiggin called
    Ender, called The Speaker For the Dead called The Xenocide
    continues .... On the world Lusitania there are now three
    sapient races-the Pequeninos, who evolved there; Humans, who
    came to colonize; and a Hive Queen and her children brought by
    Ender long years ago. But on Lusitania there is also the
    descolada, a virus deadly to human beings which would spread
    like wildfire throughout the Stairways Congress should it ever
    escape the planet. The Starways Congress decided that The
    descolada should be wiped out once and for all, and sent a
    fleet, armed with a planet-destroying weapon, to do it. A
    fourth intelligence, loyal to Ender and Lusitania caused that
    fleet to disappear. On a distant world called Path live a
    people whose culture owes much to that of ancient China on
    Earth. They have evolved a caste known as the godspoken, people
    of superior intellectual abilities who pay a terrible price for
    their gifts. The godspoken of Path have given their loyalty and
    service to the Starways Congress. Among the god spoken is a
    young girl named, in The language of her people, Gloriously
    Bright. It is to her that the Starways Congress turn with the
    mystery of the disappearance of the Lusitania Fleet. There is
    no doubt that Gloriously Bright will discover the answer to the
    puzzle. The question is, what will she do with the
    information</p>
    <p xmlns="">SUMMARY:</p>
    <p xmlns="">Orson Scott Card's Xenocide is a space opera with verve. In
    this continuation of Ender Wiggin's story, the Starways
    Congress has sent a fleet to immolate the rebellious planet of
    Lusitania, home to the alien race of pequeninos, and home to
    Ender Wiggin and his family. Concealed on Lusitania is the only
    remaining Hive Queen, who holds a secret that may save or
    destroy humanity throughout the galaxy. Familiar characters
    from the previous novels continue to grapple with religious
    conflicts and family squabbles while inventing
    faster-than-light travel and miraculous virus treatments. Throw
    into the mix an entire planet of mad geniuses and a self-aware
    computer who wants to be a martyr, and it's hard to guess who
    will topple the first domino. Due to the densely woven and
    melodramatic nature of the story, newcomers to Ender's tale
    will want to start reading this series with the first books,
    Ender's Game and Speaker for the Dead. --Brooks Peck</p>
  </content>
</entry>
