<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>The Battle of the Labyrinth</title>
  <id>urn:book:08780866-41fd-4cc9-b409-5c229f49dc08</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:18Z</updated>
  <link href="./9014e3e7%40book_378.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="The Battle of the Labyrinth" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/987b4525%40author_15_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Rick Riordan" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Labyrinth%20%28378%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Labyrinth%20%28378%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Labyrinth%20%28378%29/The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Labyrinth%20-%20Rick%20Riordan.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="290 KB" />
  <link href="../../Rick%20Riordan/The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Labyrinth%20%28378%29/The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Labyrinth%20-%20Rick%20Riordan.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="486 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Rick Riordan</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/987b4525@author_15_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2012-08-23T11:40:10Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Hyperion Book CH</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fiction:Young Adult" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Percy Jackson and the Olympians" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 4 in the Percy Jackson and the Olympians series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        Percy Jackson isn’t expecting freshman orientation
      to be any fun. But when a mysterious mortal acquaintance
      appears on campus, followed by demon cheerleaders, things
      quickly move from bad to diabolical.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>In this latest installment of the blockbuster series, time
      is running out as war between the Olympians and the evil
      Titan lord Kronos draws near. Even the safe haven of Camp
      Half-Blood grows more vulnerable by the minute as
      Kronos’s army prepares to invade its once impenetrable
      borders. To stop them, Percy and his demigod friends must set
      out on a quest through the Labyrinth—a sprawling
      underground world with stunning surprises at every turn. Full
      of humor and heart-pounding action, this fourth book promises
      to be their most thrilling adventure yet.</p>
      <h3>From School Library Journal</h3>
      <p>
        Grade 5–9—The battle starts, literally, with
      an explosion and doesn't let up. After Percy destroys the
      high school band room battling monsters called
        <em>empousai</em>
        who have taken on the form of cheerleaders,
      he has to hide out at Camp Half-Blood. There, Grover's
      searcher's license is going to be revoked unless he can find
      the god Pan in seven days. An entrance to the Labyrinth has
      been discovered, which means that Luke, the half-blood turned
      bad, can bypass the magical protections and invade the camp.
      Annabeth insists that she must follow a quest to locate
      Daedalus's workshop before Luke does. Percy is disturbed by
      visions of Nico, the son of Hades, who is summoning forth the
      spirits of the dead with McDonalds Happy Meals. Percy,
      Grover, and Percy's Cyclops half-brother follow Annabeth into
      the maze not knowing if they will ever find their way out.
      Riordan cleverly personifies the Labyrinth as a sort of
      living organism that changes at will, and that traverses the
      whole of the United States. Kids will devour Riordan's subtle
      satire of their world, such as a Sphinx in the Labyrinth
      whose questions hilariously parody standardized testing. The
      secret of Pan is revealed with a bittersweet outcome that
      also sends an eco-friendly message. Like many series, the
      "Percy Jackson" books are beginning to show the strain of
      familiarity and repetition. However, the overarching story
      line remains compelling, and the cliff-hanger ending will
      leave readers breathless in anticipation of the fifth and
      final volume.—
        <em>Tim Wadham, Maricopa County Library District, Phoenix,
      AZ</em>
        <br />
        Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division
      of Reed Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
      </p>
      <h3>About the Author</h3>
      <p>Rick Riordan is the author of all the books in the New
      York Times best-selling Percy Jackson and the Olympians
      series: The Lightning Thief, The Sea of Monsters, The Titan's
      Curse, The Battle of the Labyrinth, and The Last Olympian.
      His previous novels for adults include the hugely popular
      Tres Navarre series, winner of the top three awards in the
      mystery genre. He lives in San Antonio, Texas, with his wife
      and two sons.</p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
