<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Children of the Mind</title>
  <id>urn:book:d49c3b36-82b7-4fd1-917d-653502a782a9</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:33Z</updated>
  <link href="./91f0b983%40book_421.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Children of the Mind" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/91cd090e%40author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Children%20of%20the%20Mind%20%28421%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Children%20of%20the%20Mind%20%28421%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Children%20of%20the%20Mind%20%28421%29/Children%20of%20the%20Mind%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="383 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Children%20of%20the%20Mind%20%28421%29/Children%20of%20the%20Mind%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="537 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/91cd090e@author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2002-08-05T07:30:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Tor Books</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Fiction - Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction - General" />
  <category term="High Tech" />
  <category term="Space Opera" />
  <category term="Adventure" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Computers" />
  <category term="Artificial intelligence" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Science Fiction - High Tech" />
  <category term="Space warfare" />
  <category term="Social Issues" />
  <category term="Science Fiction - Series" />
  <category term="Wiggin; Ender (Fictitious character)" />
  <category term="Wiggin; Ender (Fictitious char" />
  <category term="Death &amp; Dying" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Ender Saga" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 4 in the Ender Saga series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Children of the Mind Orson Scott Card returns at last to the
    story of Ender Wiggin, the child hero of the Hugo and Nebula
    award winner Ender's Game, who as a man found a way to redeem
    the Xenocide of his youth and restore the Hive Queen to life.
    Now his adopted world, Lusitania, is threatened by the same
    planet-destroying weapon that he himself used so many thousands
    of years before. Lusitania is home to three sentient species:
    The Pequeninos, a strange race native to Lusitania; a large
    colony of humans; and the Hive Queen, brought there by Ender.
    But the Starways Congress fears Lusitania and a strange virus
    that it harbors, and they have gathered a fleet to destroy the
    planet. Ender's oldest friend, Jane, the computer intelligence
    that has evolved with him over three thousand years, allowed
    the Starways Congress to discover her existence when she tried
    t stop the fleet. Now they are trying to kill her as well, by
    shutting down the network of computers and ansibles in which
    she lives. They are afraid of her and of her control over all
    human communications. Jane can save the three sentient races of
    Lusitania. She has learned how to move ships outside the
    universe, and then instantly back to a different world,
    abolishing the light-speed limit. But it takes all the
    processing power available to her, and the Starways Congress is
    shutting down the Net world by world. Soon she will not be able
    to move the ships. But there is hope: during the first trip
    outside, Ender's mind briefly took control and created two new
    beings - replicas of his brother Peter, who was the Hegemon,
    and his sister Valentine. These two children of Ender's mind,
    together with his adopted children from Lusitania, are racing
    against time to discover new worlds, to influence the Starways
    Congress to recall the fleet, and to save Jane by finding a
    home for her disembodied intelligence once the Human Network is
    closed off to her.</p>
    <p xmlns="">EDITORIAL REVIEW:</p>
    <br xmlns="" />
    <br xmlns="" />
    <p xmlns="">Now in trade paperback for the first time!With Children of
    the Mind, Card returns to the story of Ender Wiggin: hero of
    the Hugo and Nebula Award-winning Enders Game, the original
    Speaker for the Dead, and the hated Xenocide who murdered an
    entire planet. Now his adopted world, Lusitania, is threatened
    by the same planet-destroying weapon that he himself used so
    many thousands of years before. Enders oldest friend, Jane, the
    computer intelligence that has evolved with him over 3000
    years, is about to be killed by the Starways Congress, which
    has finally discovered her existence and fears her control of
    the galaxy-wide interlocked network of computers and
    ansibles.Jane can save the three sentient races of Lusitaniathe
    Pequeninos, the Hive Queens daughters, and the human colony.
    She has learned how to move ships outside the universe, and
    then instantly back to a different world, abolishing the
    light-speed limit. But it takes all the processing power
    available to her, and the Starways Congress is shutting down
    the Net world by world.</p>
  </content>
</entry>
