<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Grave Peril</title>
  <id>urn:book:a62258c2-0421-4901-a42e-cc65e0750958</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:41Z</updated>
  <link href="./b7c0ea8a%40book_444.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Grave Peril" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/5a35b3d3%40author_23_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Jim Butcher" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Grave%20Peril%20%28444%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Grave%20Peril%20%28444%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Grave%20Peril%20%28444%29/Grave%20Peril%20-%20Jim%20Butcher.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="363 KB" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/Grave%20Peril%20%28444%29/Grave%20Peril%20-%20Jim%20Butcher.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="494 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Jim Butcher</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/5a35b3d3@author_23_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2001-09-02T04:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Roc</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Mystery" />
  <category term="Vampires" />
  <category term="Horror" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Dresden Files" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 3 in the Dresden Files series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>In all his years of supernatural sleuthing, Harry Dresden
      has never faced anything like this: the spirit world's gone
      postal. These ghosts are tormented, violent, and deadly.
      Someone-or something-is purposely stirring them up to wreak
      unearthly havoc. But why? If Harry doesn't figure it out
      soon, he could wind up a ghost himself.</p>
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>Wizard Harry Dresden stars in the third installment of the
      Dresden Files (following Fool Moon), a haunting, fantastical
      novel that begins almost as innocently as those of another
      famous literary wizard named Harry. In the opening scene,
      Dresden and his knight friend, Michael, battle the ghost of a
      woman who is terrorizing a local hospital's maternity ward.
      From there, the novel quickly evolves into an unorthodox tale
      spiced with sexual innuendo and subtle humor (Dresden carries
      his ghost-hunting gear in an old Scooby-Doo lunch box). Due
      to the weakened barrier between the spirit world which
      Butcher refers to as "the nevernever" and the actual world,
      obsessive and violent ghosts are on the loose in modern-day
      Chicago, and they seem to be targeting Dresden and Michael.
      Horny vampires and possessive demons join the mix as Dresden
      journeys into the spirit world to hunt down the villains who
      are terrorizing him and his friends. Butcher narrates
      Dresden's story in the first person, which limits the amount
      of detail he can inject into the lives of his secondary
      characters. Despite this narrow point of view, Butcher
      successfully lends human dimensions to vampires and spirits
      through his vivid descriptions and colloquial dialogue.
      (Sept.)Forecast: A vivid cover showing glowing barbed wire
      wrapped around a pair of cemetery gates is misleading as is a
      cover quote appealing to fans of Laurell K. Hamilton and
      Tanya Huff but it will catch the browser's eye. This
      over-the-top tale is more likely to entertain young adult
      readers than fans of the aforementioned authors.</p>
      <p>Copyright 2001 Cahners Business Information, Inc.</p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>
        Called to Cook County hospital to deal with an enraged
      ghost, Harry Dresden, Chicago's resident wizard, is puzzled
      and disturbed not by the ghost's wrath but by the fact that
      someone had cast a torture spell on it, goading it into
      action. Harry's disturbance increases when he discovers that
      the same spell has been cast on one of his friends. Harry
      begins to realize that he and his friends may be targets of a
      vengeful spirit, and as he desperately tries to discover
      which of his many enemies has it in for him, his friends are
      attacked one by one. The spirit, whom Harry refers to as the
      Nightmare, continues to torment Harry's friends until he
      manages to cast a spell preventing it from harming anyone
      else until it kills him, which leads to a showdown that Harry
      might not survive. Harry is a likable protagonist with more
      than his share of troubles, and
        <em>Grave Peril</em>
        will keep readers turning the pages to
      find out how he overcomes them.
        <em>Kristine Huntley</em>
        <br />
        <em>Copyright © American Library Association. All rights
      reserved</em>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
