<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Dark Moon</title>
  <id>urn:book:0396b82b-2784-47f6-8b75-3d1c752e4462</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:00Z</updated>
  <link href="./d26e45b9%40book_504.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Dark Moon" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/cde76a5b%40author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Dark%20Moon%20%28504%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Dark%20Moon%20%28504%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Dark%20Moon%20%28504%29/Dark%20Moon%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="403 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Dark%20Moon%20%28504%29/Dark%20Moon%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="570 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/cde76a5b@author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>1988-01-02T06:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Del Rey</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Fantasy fiction" />
  <category term="English Fiction" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        The peaceful Eldarin were the last of three ancient
      races.  The mystical Oltor, healers and poets, had
      fallen before the dread power of the cruel and sadistic
      Daroth.  Yet in one awesome night the invincible
      Daroth had vanished from the face of the
      earth.  Gone were their cities, their armies, their
      terror.  The Great Northern Desert was their only
      legacy.  Not a trace remained for a thousand
      years...
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        The War of the Pearl had raged for seven years and the
      armies of the four Duchies were exhausted and weary of
      bloodshed.  But the foremost of the Dukes, Sirano
      of Romark, possessed the Eldarin Pearl and was determined to
      unravel its secrets.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Then, on one unforgetable day, a dark moon rose above the
      Great Northern Desert, and a black tidal wave swept across
      the land.  In moments the desert had vanished
      beneath lush fields and forests and a great city could be
      seen glittering in the morning sunlight.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        From this city re-emerged the blood-hungry Daroth,
      powerful and immortal, immune to spear and
      sword.  They had only one desire:  to rid
      the world of humankind for ever.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Now the fate of the human race rests on the talents of
      three heroes:  Karis, warrior-woman and strategist;
      Tarantio, the deadliest swordsman of the age; and Duvodas the
      Healer, who will learn a terrible truth.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        A new world of myth and magic, love and heroism, from the
      bestselling author of
        <em>The Legend of Deathwalker.</em>
      </p>
      <h3>From the Inside Flap</h3>
      <p>
        The peaceful Eldarin were the last of three ancient
      races.  The mystical Oltor, healers and poets, had
      fallen before the dread power of the cruel and sadistic
      Daroth.  Yet in one awesome night the invincible
      Daroth had vanished from the face of the
      earth.  Gone were their cities, their armies, their
      terror.  The Great Northern Desert was their only
      legacy.  Not a trace remained for a thousand
      years...
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        The War of the Pearl had raged for seven years and the
      armies of the four Duchies were exhausted and weary of
      bloodshed.  But the foremost of the Dukes, Sirano
      of Romark, possessed the Eldarin Pearl and was determined to
      unravel its secrets.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Then, on one unforgetable day, a dark moon rose above the
      Great Northern Desert, and a black tidal wave swept across
      the land.  In moments the desert had vanished
      beneath lush fields and forests and a great city could be
      seen glittering in the morning sunlight.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        From this city re-emerged the blood-hungry Daroth,
      powerful and immortal, immune to spear and
      sword.  They had only one desire:  to rid
      the world of humankind for ever.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Now the fate of the human race rests on the talents of
      three heroes:  Karis, warrior-woman and strategist;
      Tarantio, the deadliest swordsman of the age; and Duvodas the
      Healer, who will learn a terrible truth.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        A new world of myth and magic, love and heroism, from the
      bestselling author of
        <em>The Legend of Deathwalker.</em>
      </p>
      <h3>Excerpt. © Reprinted by permission. All rights
      reserved.</h3>
      <p>
        <strong>Chapter One</strong>
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Tarantio was a warrior. Before that he had been a sailor,
      a miner, a breaker of horses, and an apprentice cleric to an
      elderly writer. Before that a child: quiet and solitary,
      living with a widowed father who drank in the mornings and
      wept in the afternoons.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        His mother was an acrobat in a travelling group of
      gypsies, who entertained at banquets and public gatherings.
      It was from her he inherited his nimbleness of foot, his
      speed of hand and his dark, swarthy good looks. She had died
      of the plague when Tarantio was six years old. He could
      hardly remember her now, save for one memory of a laughing
      girl-woman who threw him high in the air. From his father he
      had--he believed--inherited nothing. Save, perhaps, for the
      demon within that was Dace.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Now Tarantio was a young man and had lived with Dace for
      most of his life.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        A cold wind whispered into the cave. Tarantio's dark,
      curly hair had been shaved close to the scalp to prevent
      lice, and the draught chilled his neck. He lifted the collar
      of his heavy grey coat and, drawing one of his short swords,
      he laid it close to hand. Outside the rain was heavy, and he
      could hear water cascading down the cliff walls. The pursuers
      would surely have taken shelter somewhere.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "They may be just outside," whispered the voice of Dace in
      his mind. "Creeping up on us. Ready to cut our throats."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "You'd like that, Dace. More men to kill."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Each to his own," said Dace amiably. Tarantio was too
      tired to argue further, but Dace's intrusion made him sombre.
      Seven years ago war had descended upon the Duchies like a
      sentient hurricane, sucking men into his angry heart. And in
      the whirling maelstrom of his fury he fed them hatred and
      filled them with a love of destruction. The War Demon had
      many faces, none of them kind. Eyes of death, cloak of
      plague, mouth of famine and hands of dark despair.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        War and Dace were made for each other. Within the beast's
      hungry heart Dace was in ecstasy. Men admired him for his
      lethal skills, for his deadly talents. They sought him out as
      if he were a talisman.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Dace was a killer of men. There was a time when Tarantio
      had known how many had died under his blades. Before that,
      there was a time when he had remembered every face. Now only
      two remained firmly in his mind: the first, his eyes bulging,
      his jaw hanging slack, blood seeping over the satin sheets.
      And the second, a slim bearded thief and killer whose swords
      Tarantio now wore.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Tarantio added two logs to the fire, watching the flame
      shadows dancing on the walls of the cave. His two companions
      were stretched out on the floor, one sleeping, the other
      dying. "Why do you still think of the slaughter on the
      beach?" asked Dace. Tarantio shivered as the memories flared
      again.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Seven years ago the old ship had been beached against a
      storm, the mast dismantled, the sail wrapped and laid against
      the cliff wall. The crew were sitting around fires talking
      and laughing, playing dice. Against all odds they had
      survived the storm. They were alive, and their relieved
      laughter echoed around the cliffs, the sound drifting into
      the shadow-haunted woods beyond.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        The killers had attacked silently from those
      woods--appearing like demons, the firelight gleaming from
      raised swords and axes. The unarmed sailors had no chance and
      were hacked down without mercy, their blood staining the
      sand.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Tarantio, as always, had been sitting away from the
      others, lying on his back in the rocks, staring up at the
      distant stars. At the first screams he had rolled to his
      knees, and watched the slaughter in the moonlight. Unarmed
      and unskilled, the young sailor had been powerless to help
      his comrades. Crouching down he hid, trembling, on the cold
      stones, the incoming tide lapping at his legs. He could hear
      the thieves plundering the ship, tearing open the hatches and
      unloading the booty. Spices and liquor from the islands,
      silks from the southern continent, and a shipment of silver
      ingots bound for the mint at Loretheli.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Towards dawn one of the attackers had walked into the
      rocks to relieve himself. Terror filled Tarantio with panic
      and Dace rose within him, flaring like a light within the
      skull. Dace reared up before the astonished reaver, crashing
      a fist-size rock against the man's head. The thief pitched
      forward without a sound. Dragging him out of sight of his
      comrades, Dace drew a knife from the man's belt and stabbed
      him to death.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        The dead man wore two short swords, their black hilts
      tightly bound with leather. Dace had unbuckled the sword-belt
      and swung it around his own waist. Relieving the man of his
      bulging purse, Dace had stolen away through the rocks,
      leaving the scene of the massacre far behind.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Once clear, the panic gone, Tarantio dragged Dace back and
      resumed control. Dace had not objected; without the prospect
      of violence, and the need to kill, he was easily bored.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Alone and friendless, Tarantio had walked the thirty miles
      west to the Corsair city of Loretheli, looking for a berth on
      a new ship. Instead he had met Sigellus the Swordsman.
      Tarantio thought of him often, and of the perils they had
      faced together. But the thoughts were always tinged with
      sadness and the velvet claw of regret at his death. Sigellus
      had understood about Dace. During one of their training
      sessions Dace had broken loose, and had tried to kill
      Sigellus. The swordsman had been too skilled for him then,
      but Dace managed to cut him before Sigellus blocked a thrust
      and hammered his iron fist into Dace's chin, spinning him
      from his feet.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "What the Hell is wrong with you, boy?" he had asked, when
      Tarantio regained consciousness. For the second time in his
      young life, he talked about Dace. Sigellus had listened, his
      grey eyes expressionless, blood dripping from a shallow cut
      to his right cheek just below the eye. When at last he had
      told it all, including the murders, Sigellus sat back and let
      out a deep sigh. "All men carry demons, Chio," he said. "At
      least you have made an effort to control yours. May I speak
      with Dace?"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "You don't think I am insane?"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "I do not know what you are, my boy. But let me speak with
      Dace."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "He can hear you, sir," said Tarantio. "I do not wish to
      let him free."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Very well. Hear me, Dace, you fight with great passion,
      and you are uncannily fast. But it will take you time to
      learn to be half as good as I am. So understand this. If you
      try to kill me again, I will spear your belly and gut you
      like a fish." He looked into Chio's dark blue eyes. "Did he
      understand that?"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Yes, sir. He understood."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "That is good." Sigellus had smiled then, and, with a silk
      handkerchief he had mopped the trickle of blood from his
      face. "Now I think that is enough practice for today. I can
      hear a jug of wine calling my name."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "I hate him," said Dace. "One day I will kill him."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "That is a lie," Tarantio told him. "You don't hate him at
      all."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        For a time Dace was silent. When at last his voice
      whispered into Tarantio's mind it was softer than at any time
      before. "He is the first person, apart from you, to ever
      speak to me. To speak to Dace."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        In that instant Tarantio felt a surge of jealousy. "He
      threatened to kill you," he pointed out.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "He said I was good. Uncannily fast."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "He is my friend."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "You want me to kill him?"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "No!"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Then you must let him be my friend too."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Tarantio shivered and pushed the painful memories from his
      mind.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        The War of the Pearl had begun, and the Four Duchies were
      recruiting fighting men. Few had even seen the artefact they
      were willing to kill--or die--for. Fewer still understood the
      importance of the Pearl. Rumours were rife: it was a weapon
      of enormous power; it was a healing stone which could grant
      immortality; it was a prophetic jewel which could read the
      future. No-one really knew.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        After his time with Sigellus, he and Dace had wandered
      through the warring Duchies, taking employment with various
      mercenary units and twice holding commissions in regular
      forces, taking part in sieges, cavalry attacks, minor
      skirmishes and several pitched battles. Mostly they had the
      good fortune to be with the victorious side, but four times
      they had--as now--been among the refugees of a ruined army.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        The camp-fire burned low in the shallow cave and Tarantio
      sat before it, the heat barely reaching his cold hands. By
      the far wall lay Kiriel, his life fading. Belly wounds were
      always the worst, and this one was particularly bad, having
      severed the intestines. The boy moaned and cried out.
      Tarantio moved to him, laying his fingers over the boy's
      mouth. "Be strong, Kiriel. Be silent. The enemy are close."
      Kiriel's fever-bright eyes opened. They were cornflower blue,
      the eyes of a child, frightened and longing for reassurance.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "I am hurting, Tarantio," he whispered. "Am I dying?"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Dying? From a little scratch like that? You just rest. By
      dawn you'll feel like wrestling a bear."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Truly?"
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Truly," lied Tarantio, knowing that by dawn the boy would
      be dead. Kiriel closed his eyes. Tarantio stroked his blond
      hair until he slept, then returned to the fire. A huge figure
      stirred by the far wall, then rose and sat opposite the
      warrior.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "To lie is a kindness sometimes," said the big man softly,
      firelight reflecting in his twin-forked red beard, his green
      eyes shining like cold jewels. "I think the thrust must have
      burst his spleen. The wound stinks."
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>Tarantio nodded, then added the last of the fuel to the
      fire as the other man chuckled. "Thought we were finished
      back there--until you attacked them. I have to be honest,
      Tarantio, I had heard of your skills but never believed the
      stories. Shem's tits, but I do now! Never seen the like. I'm
      j...</p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
