<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Speaker for the Dead</title>
  <id>urn:book:822cc077-177f-4661-8f6f-64f02a885316</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:34Z</updated>
  <link href="./e19a4d0c%40book_424.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Speaker for the Dead" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/91cd090e%40author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Speaker%20for%20the%20Dead%20%28424%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Speaker%20for%20the%20Dead%20%28424%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Speaker%20for%20the%20Dead%20%28424%29/Speaker%20for%20the%20Dead%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="398 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Speaker%20for%20the%20Dead%20%28424%29/Speaker%20for%20the%20Dead%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="581 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/91cd090e@author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2010-02-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Time Warner Books Uk</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Wiggin; Ender (Fictitious character)" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Ender Saga" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 2 in the Ender Saga series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Speaker for the Dead Nebula and Hugo Award Winner
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Three thousand planet-bound years have fled since Ender Wiggin
    won humanity's war with the Buggers by totally destroying them.
    Ender remains young-travelling the stars at relativistic
    speeds, a hundred years or more might pass while he experiences
    a month-long voyage. In three thousand years, his books The
    Hive Queen and The Hegemon have become holy writ, and the name
    of Ender anathema; he is the Xenocide, the one who killed an
    entire race of thinking, feeling beings, the only other sapient
    race humankind had found in all the galaxy. The only ones, that
    is, until the planet called Lusitania was discovered and
    colonized. On Lusitania humans found another race of ramen ...
    a young race, beings just beginning to lift their eyes to the
    stars and wonder what might be out there. The discovery was
    seen as a gift to humanity, a chance to redeem the destruction
    of the Buggers. And so the Pequininos, as they were named by
    the portuguese-speaking settlers, the "Piggies," were placed
    off-limits to the colony. The only humans allowed to meet them
    and speak with them are trained xenobiologists, and then only
    two at a time. This time, there will be no tragic
    misunderstandings leading to war. This time... This time,
    again, men die -bizarrely killed by the Piggies. Andrew Wiggin
    is called to Lusitania to Speak the deaths of the two
    xenobiologists, and walks into a maelstrom of fear and hatred.
    To Speak for these dead, he must first unravel the web of
    secrets surrounding the lives of the Piggies and those who
    study them. He must Speak not only for the dead, but for a
    living alien race. This magnificent sequel to ENDER'S GAME won
    both the Hugo Award and the Nebula Award for Best SF Novel of
    the Year. Orson Scott Card is one of the finest, most
    innovative writers of the past decade, whose works also include
    the acclaimed alternate world fantasy series, The Tales of
    Alvin Maker. Copyright © 1986 Orson Scott Card A Tor Book
    - Published by Tom Doherty Associates, Inc. Jacket art by John
    Harris - Jacket design by Carol Russo</p>
    <p xmlns="">EDITORIAL REVIEW:</p>
    <br xmlns="" />
    <br xmlns="" />
    <p xmlns="">Three thousand planet-bound years have passed while Ender
    the star-traveller remains young. In that time his name has
    become anathema, for he is the one who killed an entire race of
    thinking, feeling beings. No other has been found - until
    Lusitania is discovered. The young race there offers mankind a
    chance to redeem the previous destruction. The only humans
    allowed near are trained xenobiologists. But once again there
    are tragic misunderstandings. And when Ender, as Andrew Wiggin,
    is called to Lusitania to speak for the dead - to present to
    the community the terrible truth of why men have been killed by
    aliens - his actions can, and will, reverberate through an
    entire galactic empire.</p>
  </content>
</entry>
