<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>White Night</title>
  <id>urn:book:d930b629-af95-4fc7-bf5c-75fc00ed3e63</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:38Z</updated>
  <link href="./f1373066%40book_438.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="White Night" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/5a35b3d3%40author_23_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Jim Butcher" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/White%20Night%20%28438%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/White%20Night%20%28438%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/White%20Night%20%28438%29/White%20Night%20-%20Jim%20Butcher.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="348 KB" />
  <link href="../../Jim%20Butcher/White%20Night%20%28438%29/White%20Night%20-%20Jim%20Butcher.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="540 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Jim Butcher</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/5a35b3d3@author_23_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2007-01-01T05:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Roc</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Contemporary" />
  <category term="Mystery" />
  <category term="Vampires" />
  <category term="Fantasy - Epic" />
  <category term="Fiction - Fantasy" />
  <category term="Fantasy - Contemporary" />
  <category term="American Science Fiction And Fantasy" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Dresden Files" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 9 in the Dresden Files series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        <strong>The inspiration for the Sci Fi channel television
        series</strong>
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        In Chicago, someone has been killing practitioners of
      magic, those incapable of becoming full-fledged wizards.
      Shockingly, all the evidence points to Harry Dresden's
      half-brother, Thomas, as the murderer. Determined to clear
      his sibling's name, Harry uncovers a conspiracy within the
      White Council of Wizards that threatens not only him, but his
      nearest and dearest, too...
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>The Dabel Brothers are bringing the Dresden Files
        to life in comic book form—look for issues beginning
        April 2008! View more here!</strong>
      </p>
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>
        <em>Starred Review.</em>
        At the start of Butcher's
      superlative ninth Dresden Files novel (after 2006's
        <em>Proven Guilty</em>
        ), hardboiled wizard detective Harry
      Dresden learns that someone is killing Chicago's minor
      wizards. Joined by his police friend, Sergeant Murphy, and
      his Amazonian apprentice, Molly Carpenter, Harry discovers
      that his brother, Thomas, is a prime suspect. As a Warden of
      the White Council, at war with both the Red Court of
      blood-drinking vampires and the White Court of psychic
      vampires, Harry has to go into action. And there's plenty of
      that, including a battle with ghouls on the lakefront that
      turns into a gripping flashback of another encounter with
      ghouls some years before in New Mexico. The large cast
      features such finely drawn characters as gangster Gentleman
      Johnnie Marcone and Harry's first love, Elaine Mallory. This
      installment is sure to get a lift from
        <em>The Dresden Files</em>
        TV series, which debuted on the
      Sci-Fi Channel in January.
        <em>Author tour. (Apr.)</em>
        <br />
        Copyright © Reed Business Information, a division
      of Reed Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
      </p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>
        <em>Starred Review</em>
        This time, when Harry Dresden gets a
      call from Murphy, it's off the record, because she has been
      demoted, things in SI are politically shaky, and the police
      have already declared a suicide. Once Harry gets a good look,
      though, the suicide is clearly a murder with magical intent.
      As he investigates, hoping as always to stop the killer
      before more die, evidence points to the worst possible
      suspect: his half brother. In another complicated case, there
      are a lot of very powerful players, and with the war between
      the White Council and the Red Court vampires, politics are
      played hard and fast. In tracking down the killer, Harry
      manages to catch the attention of the White Court vampires
      again, too. On top of all that, he is still teaching
      strong-willed, occasionally impulsive teenager Molly
      Carpenter, and the teacher-student dynamic is difficult for
      him. And oh, yes, Lasciel, the demon trapped in a coin Harry
      has secured under his summoning circle, is a lingering
      presence. As usual in the Dresden Files, of which this is
      volume 9, Butcher puts the characters in a lot of danger,
      creates appalling moral choices for them, and spins an
      excellent noirish detective yarn in a well-crafted,
      supernaturally charged setting. The supporting cast is again
      fantastic, and Harry's wit continues to fly in the face of a
      peril-fraught plot.
        <em>Regina Schroeder</em>
        <br />
        <em>Copyright © American Library Association. All rights
      reserved</em>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
