<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Ender's Game</title>
  <id>urn:book:fbf47d44-729c-4021-a02c-ef6f42a076f1</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:35Z</updated>
  <link href="./f942c20%40book_426.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Ender's Game" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/91cd090e%40author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Game%20%28426%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Game%20%28426%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Game%20%28426%29/Ender%27s%20Game%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="321 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Game%20%28426%29/Ender%27s%20Game%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="471 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/91cd090e@author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2010-01-31T07:30:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Topeka Bindery</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction - General" />
  <category term="Children: Young Adult (Gr. 7-9)" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Children's Books" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Ages 9-12 Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction; Fantasy; &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Brothers and sisters" />
  <category term="Wiggin; Ender (Fictitious character)" />
  <category term="Wiggin; Ender (Fictitious char" />
  <category term="Genetic engineering" />
  <category term="Children's 9-12 - Fiction - Science Fiction" />
  <category term="War games" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Ender Saga" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Ender Saga series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Ender's Game Nebula and Hugo Award Winner
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
    From its first publication in January 1985, Ender's Game
    quickly became a classic in the science fiction field. It was
    greeted enthusiastically by the Science Fiction Writers of
    America, which gave it the Nebula Award for best novel of 1985,
    and the 1986 World Science Fiction Convention awarded Ender's
    Game the best novel Hugo. (What really stunned everyone was the
    following year, when the sequel, Speaker for the Dead, also won
    both awards -- something no author had ever done before, still
    less for a book and its sequel!) While Card has gone on to win
    other awards (two more Hugos, a World Fantasy Award, and in
    1996 the Locus Award for Best Fantasy Novel of the year for his
    book Alvin Journeyman), Ender's Game continues to be his most
    popular novel, capturing the imagination of children,
    teenagers, and adults. Ender's Game has been translated into
    French, German, Spanish, Japanese, Dutch, Czech, Danish,
    Finnish, Hebrew, Hungarian, Italian, Polish, Portuguese,
    Romanian, Russian, and Swedish. Why does the story work so
    well? Many people call it "the science fiction novel for people
    who don't think they like science fiction." While the trappings
    of science fiction are there -- spaceships, aliens, futuristic
    machinery -- the reason the book works for so many people is
    that it's first and foremost a human story, of a boy who finds
    the burdens of the world placed on his back. Isolated and
    alone, his anguish resonates in the hearts of all readers. Yes,
    kids who read the book really enjoy the whole idea of the
    Battle School, a three-dimensional playspace where children in
    special suits have mock combats between armies. Others are
    intrigued by the military aspects of the book. When the Marine
    University at Quantico required students in one class to read
    Ender's Game, it wasn't for the strategy -- tactics in 3D space
    aren't really a big deal for the Marines. Rather, it was
    because Ender's Game is virtually a textbook in how to develop
    a strong relationship between a commander and his troops --
    with plenty of examples also in how to fail as a commander.
    Other people -- especially in the online community -- love
    Ender's Game because of the powerful role it shows for computer
    networks in the world of the future. The Internet has taken a
    few steps in the direction shown by Ender's Game, but we're
    still a long way from a time when public discourse takes place
    primarily on the Internet and e-discussions can influence
    public policy. So Ender's Game is still a dream. Yet others
    find the "Mind Game" most appealing. This is the computer game
    that students in the Battle School play, allowing their
    teachers to evaluate their emotional state. Ender, however,
    forces the computer to reprogram itself to allow him to play
    the game in new, unpredictable ways. The whole idea of a
    self-altering game that responds to the needs and desires of
    the player still intrigues many -- though Card has still not
    been able to persuade any computer game publishers to develop a
    self-creating game! Above all, though, Ender's Game is the
    story of growing up alone, trying to find independence when
    none is allowed, trying to find meaning in a life whose meaning
    has already been defined. Almost everyone has at some time felt
    himself or herself to be in the same kind of no-win situation
    as Ender Wiggin, and the triumph of the book is not that Ender
    Wiggin "wins," but that he grows up along the way.
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Copyright © 1985 Orson Scott Card A Tor Book - Published
    by Tom Doherty Associates, Inc. Jacket art by John Harris -
    Jacket design by Carol Russo</p>
    <p xmlns="">SUMMARY:</p>
    <p xmlns="">Winner of the Hugo and Nebula AwardsIn order to develop a
    secure defense against a hostile alien race's next attack,
    government agencies breed child geniuses and train them as
    soldiers. A brilliant young boy, Andrew "Ender" Wiggin lives
    with his kind but distant parents, his sadistic brother Peter,
    and the person he loves more than anyone else, his sister
    Valentine. Peter and Valentine were candidates for the
    soldier-training program but didn't make the cut—young
    Ender is the Wiggin drafted to the orbiting Battle School for
    rigorous military training.Ender's skills make him a leader in
    school and respected in the Battle Room, where children play at
    mock battles in zero gravity. Yet growing up in an artificial
    community of young soldiers Ender suffers greatly from
    isolation, rivalry from his peers, pressure from the adult
    teachers, and an unsettling fear of the alien invaders. His
    psychological battles include loneliness, fear that he is
    becoming like the cruel brother he remembers, and fanning the
    flames of devotion to his beloved sister. Is Ender the general
    Earth needs? But Ender is not the only result of the genetic
    experiments. The war with the Buggers has been raging for a
    hundred years, and the quest for the perfect general has been
    underway for almost as long. Ender's two older siblings are
    every bit as unusual as he is, but in very different ways.
    Between the three of them lie the abilities to remake a world.
    If, that is, the world survives.</p>
  </content>
</entry>
