<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Inkheart</title>
  <id>urn:book:7025e5ac-7809-4467-8932-d2191053b9e0</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:10Z</updated>
  <link href="./f943167a%40book_534.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Inkheart" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722@index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40authorlist/e8e4356e%40authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../76bdb722%40author_0/3429b204%40author_32_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Cornelia Funke" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkheart%20%28534%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkheart%20%28534%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkheart%20%28534%29/Inkheart%20-%20Cornelia%20Funke.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="373 KB" />
  <link href="../../Cornelia%20Funke/Inkheart%20%28534%29/Inkheart%20-%20Cornelia%20Funke.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="578 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Cornelia Funke</name>
    <uri>../76bdb722@author_0/3429b204@author_32_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2003-01-02T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Scholastic Inc.</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Family" />
  <category term="Language Arts &amp; Disciplines" />
  <category term="Authorship" />
  <category term="Parents" />
  <category term="_nocatalog" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Inkheart" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Inkheart series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">From internationally acclaimed storyteller Cornelia Funke,
    this bestselling, magical epic is now out in paperback!One
    cruel night, Meggie's father reads aloud from a book called
    INKHEART-- and an evil ruler escapes the boundaries of fiction
    and lands in their living room. Suddenly, Meggie is smack in
    the middle of the kind of adventure she has only read about in
    books. Meggie must learn to harness the magic that has conjured
    this nightmare. For only she can change the course of the story
    that has changed her life forever. This is INKHEART--a timeless
    tale about books, about imagination, about life. Dare to read
    it aloud.</p>
    <h3 xmlns="">Amazon.com Review</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Meggie’s father, Mo, has an wonderful and sometimes
    terrible ability. When he reads aloud from books, he brings the
    characters to life--literally. Mo discovered his power when
    Maggie was just a baby. He read so lyrically from the the book
      <em>Inkheart,</em>
      that several of the book’s wicked
    characters ended up blinking and cursing on his cottage floor.
    Then Mo discovered something even worse--when he read Capricorn
    and his henchmen
      <em>out</em>
      of Inkheart, he accidentally read Meggie’s
    mother
      <em>in.</em>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Meggie, now a young lady, knows nothing of her father's
    bizarre and powerful talent, only that Mo still refuses to read
    to her. Capricorn, a being so evil he would "feed a bird to a
    cat on purpose, just to watch it being torn apart," has
    searched for Meggie's father for years, wanting to twist Mo's
    powerful talent to his own dark means. Finally, Capricorn
    realizes that the best way to lure Mo to his remote mountain
    hideaway is to use his beloved, oblivious daughter Meggie as
    bait!</p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Cornelia Funke’s imaginative ode to books and book
    lovers is sure to be enjoyed by fans of her breakout debut,
      <em>The Thief Lord</em>
      , and young readers who enjoyed the
    similarly themed
      <em>The Great Good Thing</em>
      by Roderick Townley. (Ages 10 to
    15)
      <em>--Jennifer Hubert</em>
    </p>
    <h3 xmlns="">From School Library Journal</h3>
    <p xmlns="">
      Grade 4-8-Characters from books literally leap off the page
    in this engrossing fantasy. Meggie, 12, has had her father to
    herself since her mother went away when she was young. Mo
    taught her to read when she was five, and the two share a
    mutual love of books. Things change after a visit from a
    scarred man who calls himself Dustfinger and who refers to Mo
    as Silvertongue. Meggie learns that her father has been keeping
    secrets. He can "read" characters out of books. When she was
    three, he read aloud from a book called Inkheart and released
    Dustfinger and other characters into the real world. At the
    same time, Meggie's mother disappeared into the story. Mo also
    released Capricorn, a sadistic villain who takes great pleasure
    in murdering people. He has sent his black-coated henchmen to
    track down Mo and intends to force him to read an immortal
    monster out of the story to get rid of his enemies. Meggie, Mo,
    Dustfinger, and Meggie's great-aunt Elinor are pursued,
    repeatedly captured, but manage to escape from Capricorn's
    henchmen as they attempt to find the author of Inkheart in the
    hope that he can write a new ending to the story. This "story
    within a story" will delight not just fantasy fans, but all
    readers who like an exciting plot with larger-than-life
    characters. Pair this title with Roderick Townley's The Great
    Good Thing (2001) and Into the Labyrinth (2002, both Atheneum)
    for a wonderful exploration of worlds within words.
      <br />
      <em>Sharon Rawlins, Piscataway Public Library, NJ</em>
      <br />
      Copyright 2003 Reed Business Information, Inc.
    </p>
  </content>
</entry>
