<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>White Wolf</title>
  <id>urn:book:3126cb0c-28c4-4dc0-b588-7cc6001348b5</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:57Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_493.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="White Wolf" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/White%20Wolf%20%28493%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/White%20Wolf%20%28493%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/White%20Wolf%20%28493%29/White%20Wolf%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="394 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/White%20Wolf%20%28493%29/White%20Wolf%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="607 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2003-01-02T06:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Del Rey</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Drenai" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 10 in the Drenai series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        <strong>White Wolf</strong>
        marks a return to the bestselling
      Drenai series and David Gemmell’s most popular hero of
      all, Druss the Legend.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Skilgannon the Damned had vanished from the pages of
      history. No-one knew where he had gone, following the
      terrible triumph at Perapolis, and the assasins sent by the
      Witch Queen could find no trace of his passing. Three years
      later, a murderous mob gathers outside a monastery, faced by
      a single, unarmed priest. In a few terrifying seconds their
      world is changed for ever, and word spreads across the lands
      of the East -- Skilgannon is back.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        Now he must travel across a perilous, demon-haunted realm
      seeking a mysterious temple and the ageless goddess who rules
      it. With assassins on his trail and an army of murderous foes
      ahead, the Damned sets off on a quest to bring the dead to
      life. But he does not travel alone. The man beside him is
      Druss the Legend.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        In this tale of love, betrayal and treachery, in a world
      torn by war,
        <strong>White Wolf</strong>
        examines the nature of heroism
      and friendship and the narrow lines dividing good and evil.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <em>From the Trade Paperback edition.</em>
      </p>
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>
        This new heroic fantasy in Gemmell's engrossing Drenai
      series takes place immediately before his first published
      novel, Legend (1984), but stands well on its own. Skilgannon,
      swordmaster and former general of Queen Jianna's army, walked
      away from the queen's service after his forces sacked a city
      with such savagery that his name is ever after followed by
      "the Damned." He's spent three trying years submitting to
      monastic discipline in hopes of understanding the places of
      man and evil in the world. His dreams are disturbed by a
      white wolf; his thoughts by memories of his dead wife and
      hopeless love for Queen Jianna. Now the surrounding town is
      torn by civil unrest and the monks debate fleeing: Skilgannon
      might have stayed with them but for the price on his head and
      the futility of his disguise as Brother Lantern. The abbot
      sends him to the capital, Mellicane, escorting an unworldly
      monk. In the woods outside town, they pick up the boy
      Rabalyn, whose troubles with a town bully ended with the
      torching of his aunt's house and the killing of the aunt and
      the bully; his ne'er-do-well parents are said to be in the
      capital. Thus begins a journey that will continue beyond
      Mellicane and draw in the author's most famous character,
      Druss the axeman. The plot seamlessly supports the
      predictable violence. Magic plays little part in everyday
      life, but when it affects the deeds of rulers and leaders,
      Gemmell describes it in a concrete, nuts-and-bolts way in
      welcome contrast to much airy-fairy fantasy.
        <br />
        Copyright 2003 Reed Business Information, Inc.
      </p>
      <h3>From Booklist</h3>
      <p>
        The prolific Gemmell returns to the violence-ridden world
      of the Drenai and his best-known character, wandering warrior
      Druss the Legend, and in opening this book, introduces
      another, even more Conanesque figure, Skilgannon--tattooed
      with a spider on his arm and a leopard on his chest, and
      haunted by dreams of a white wolf. The dreams and other
      circumstances don't improve Skilgannon's already hair-trigger
      temper, and on first meeting Druss, the two bristle at each
      other like tomcats. They face a common foe, however: the
      werebeasts known as Joinings, who endanger not only the two
      warriors but all Drenai. Under those circumstances, suspicion
      slowly turns to cooperation, and cooperation to a friendship
      that makes their partnership significant in Drenai's history
      as well as the pretext for a multitude of good battle scenes!
      Standing more or less independent of previous Druss novels,
        <em>White Wolf</em>
        is a good introduction to them and a
      typical, action-oriented Gemmell-brand fantasy.
        <em>Roland Green</em>
        <br />
        <em>Copyright © American Library Association. All rights
      reserved</em>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
