<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Ender's Shadow</title>
  <id>urn:book:38d452cf-9354-46c9-8de9-1d2f53b19c52</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:32Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_416.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Ender's Shadow" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Shadow%20%28416%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Shadow%20%28416%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Shadow%20%28416%29/Ender%27s%20Shadow%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="423 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Ender%27s%20Shadow%20%28416%29/Ender%27s%20Shadow%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="614 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2010-02-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Rebound by Sagebrush</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction - General" />
  <category term="Juvenile Fiction" />
  <category term="Children's Books" />
  <category term="Fantasy &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Ages 9-12 Fiction" />
  <category term="Science Fiction; Fantasy; &amp; Magic" />
  <category term="Children: Young Adult (Gr. 10-12)" />
  <category term="Children's 9-12 - Fiction - Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Shadow Quintet" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Shadow Quintet series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">Ender's Shadow : A Parallel Novel to Ender's Game Orson
    Scott Card brings us back to the very beginning of his
    brilliant Ender's Quartet, with a novel that allows us to
    reenter that world anew. With all the power of his original
    creation, Card has created a parallel volume to Ender's Game, a
    book that expands and complements the first, enhancing its
    power, illuminating its events and its powerful conclusion. The
    human race is at War with the "Buggers," an insect-like alien
    race. The first battles went badly, and now as Earth prepares
    to defend itself against the imminent threat of total
    destruction at the hands of an inscrutable alien enemy, all
    focus is on the development and training of military geniuses
    who can fight such a war, and win. The long distances of
    interstellar space have given hope to the defenders of Earth
    — they have time to train these future commanders up from
    childhood, forging them into an irresistible force in the
    high-orbital facility called the Battle School. Andrew "Ender"
    Wiggin was not the only child in the Battle School; he was just
    the best of the best. In this new book, Card tells the story of
    another of those precocious generals, the one they called Bean
    — the one who became Ender's right hand, his strategist,
    and his friend. One who was with him, part of his team, in the
    final battle against the Buggers. Bean's past was a battle just
    to survive. He first appeared on the streets of Rotterdam, a
    tiny child with a mind leagues beyond anyone else's. He knew he
    could not survive through strength; he used his tactical genius
    to gain acceptance into a children's gang, and then to help
    make that gang a template for success for all the others. He
    civilized them, and lived to grow older. Bean's desperate
    struggle to live, and his success, brought him to the attention
    of the Battle School's recruiters, those people scouring the
    planet for leaders, tacticians, and generals to save Earth from
    the threat of alien invasion. Bean was sent into orbit, to the
    Battle School. And there he met Ender...</p>
    <p xmlns="">SUMMARY:</p>
    <p xmlns="">Ender's Shadow is being dubbed as a parallel novel to Orson
    Scott Card's Hugo and Nebula Award-winning Ender's Game. By
    "parallel," Card means that Shadow begins and ends at roughly
    the same time as Game, and it chronicles many of the same
    events. In fact, the two books tell an almost identical story
    of brilliant children being trained in the orbiting Battle
    School to lead humanity's fleets in the final war against alien
    invaders known as the Buggers. The most brilliant of these
    young recruits is Ender Wiggin, an unparalleled commander and
    tactician who can surely defeat the Buggers if only he can
    overcome his own inner turmoil. Second among the children is
    Bean, who becomes Ender's lieutenant despite the fact that he
    is the smallest and youngest of the Battle School students.
    Bean is the central character of Shadow, and we pick up his
    story when he is just a 2-year-old starving on the streets of a
    future Rotterdam that has become a hell on earth. Bean is
    unnaturally intelligent for his age, which is the only thing
    that allows him to escape--though not unscathed--the streets
    and eventually end up in Battle School. Despite his brilliance,
    however, Bean is doomed to live his life as an also-ran to the
    more famous and in many ways more brilliant Ender. Nonetheless,
    Bean learns things that Ender cannot or will not understand,
    and it falls to this once pathetic street urchin to carry the
    weight of a terrible burden that Ender must not be allowed to
    know. Although it may seem like Shadow is merely an attempt by
    Card to cash in on the success of his justly famous Ender's
    Game, that suspicion will dissipate once you turn the first few
    pages of this engrossing novel. It's clear that Bean has a
    story worth telling, and that Card (who started the project
    with a cowriter but later decided he wanted it all to himself)
    is driven to tell it. And though much of Ender's Game hinges on
    a surprise ending that Card fans are likely well acquainted
    with, Shadow manages to capitalize on that same surprise and
    even turn the table on readers. In the end, it seems a shame
    that Shadow, like Bean himself, will forever be eclipsed by the
    myth of Ender, because this is a novel that can easily stand on
    its own. Luckily for readers, Card has left plenty of room for
    a sequel, so we may well be seeing more of Bean in the near
    future. --Craig E. Engler</p>
  </content>
</entry>
