<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</title>
  <id>urn:book:7db52dab-7e60-45fb-9e0a-86041fc9e0d2</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:44Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_455.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_24_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="J. K. Rowling" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Order%20of%20the%20P%20%28455%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Order%20of%20the%20P%20%28455%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Order%20of%20the%20P%20%28455%29/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Order%20of%20t%20-%20J.%20K.%20Rowling.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <link href="../../J.%20K.%20Rowling/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Order%20of%20the%20P%20%28455%29/Harry%20Potter%20and%20the%20Order%20of%20t%20-%20J.%20K.%20Rowling.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="1 MB" />
  <author>
    <name>J. K. Rowling</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_24_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>0101-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <category term="child_adv" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Harry Potter" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 5 in the Harry Potter series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">As his fifth year at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and
    Wizardry approaches, 15-year-old Harry Potter is in full-blown
    adolescence, complete with regular outbursts of rage, a nearly
    debilitating crush, and the blooming of a powerful sense of
    rebellion. It’s been yet another infuriating and boring
    summer with the despicable Dursleys, this time with minimal
    contact from our hero’s non-Muggle friends from school.
    Harry is feeling especially edgy at the lack of news from the
    magic world, wondering when the freshly revived evil Lord
    Voldemort will strike. Returning to Hogwarts will be a
    relief… or will it? The fifth book in
    J. K. Rowling’s Harry Potter series follows the
    darkest year yet for our young wizard, who finds himself
    knocked down a peg or three after the events of last year.
    Somehow, over the summer, gossip (usually traced back to the
    magic world’s newspaper, the Daily Prophet ) has turned
    Harry’s tragic and heroic encounter with Voldemort at the
    Triwizard Tournament into an excuse to ridicule and discount
    the teen. Even Professor Dumbledore, headmaster of the school,
    has come under scrutiny by the Ministry of Magic, which refuses
    to officially acknowledge the terrifying truth that Voldemort
    is back. Enter a particularly loathsome new character: the
    toadlike and simpering (“ hem, hem” ) Dolores
    Umbridge, senior undersecretary to the Minister of Magic, who
    takes over the vacant position of Defense Against Dark Arts
    teacher—and in no time manages to become the High
    Inquisitor of Hogwarts, as well. Life isn’t getting any
    easier for Harry Potter. With an overwhelming course load as
    the fifth years prepare for their Ordinary Wizarding Levels
    examinations (O.W.Ls), devastating changes in the Gryffindor
    Quidditch team lineup, vivid dreams about long hallways and
    closed doors, and increasing pain in his lightning-shaped scar,
    Harry’s resilience is sorely tested. Harry Potter and the
    Order of the Phoenix , more than any of the four previous
    novels in the series, is a coming-of-age story. Harry faces the
    thorny transition into adulthood, when adult heroes are
    revealed to be fallible, and matters that seemed
    black-and-white suddenly come out in shades of gray. Gone is
    the wide-eyed innocent, the whiz kid of Sorcerer’s Stone
    . Here we have an adolescent who’s sometimes sullen,
    often confused (especially about girls), and always
    self-questioning. Confronting death again, as well as a
    startling prophecy, Harry ends his year at Hogwarts exhausted
    and pensive. Readers, on the other hand, will be energized as
    they enter yet again the long waiting period for the next title
    in the marvelous, magical series.</p>
  </content>
</entry>
