<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Earth Awakens</title>
  <id>urn:book:f52a0754-df46-4574-a52d-ef4a92722c2d</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:30Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_411.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Earth Awakens" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Earth%20Awakens%20%28411%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Earth%20Awakens%20%28411%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Earth%20Awakens%20%28411%29/Earth%20Awakens%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="807 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/Earth%20Awakens%20%28411%29/Earth%20Awakens%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="643 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2014-06-10T05:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Tor Books</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="First Formic War" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 3 in the First Formic War series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        The story of The First Formic War continues in
        <em>Earth Awakens</em>
        .
      </p>
      <p>
        Nearly 100 years before the events of Orson Scott
      Card’s bestselling novel
        <em>Ender’s Game</em>
        , humans were just beginning to
      step off Earth and out into the Solar System. A thin web of
      ships in both asteroid belts; a few stations; a corporate
      settlement on Luna. No one had seen any sign of other
      space-faring races; everyone expected that First Contact, if
      it came, would happen in the future, in the empty reaches
      between the stars. Then a young navigator on a distant mining
      ship saw something moving too fast, heading directly for our
      sun.
      </p>
      <p>When the alien ship screamed through the solar system, it
      disrupted communications between the far-flung human mining
      ships and supply stations, and between them and Earth. So
      Earth and Luna were unaware that they had been invaded until
      the ship pulled into Earth orbit, and began landing
      terra-forming crews in China. Politics and pride slowed the
      response on Earth, and on Luna, corporate power struggles
      seemed more urgent than distant deaths. But there are a few
      men and women who see that if Earth doesn’t wake up and
      pull together, the planet could be lost.</p>
      <p>**</p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>
        Praise for
        <em>Earth Afire</em>
      </p>
      <p>
        “The sections that feature highly intelligent,
      self-reliant children—Card’s trademark—are
      as excellent as ever; elsewhere there’s plenty of solid
      action, well-developed characters….Another solidly
      engrossing installment, where the aliens are really just a
      sideshow: What we’re witnessing is how and why
      Ender’s child armies came to be.” —
        <em>Kirkus Reviews</em>
      </p>
      <p>“While the reader knows who wins the war, the fate
      of the engaging characters in this story is up in the air.
      Thirty-five years after he introduced Ender to the world,
      it’s great to see that Orson Scott Card is still making
      magic in this imaginative world.” —*NY Journal of
      Books</p>
      <p>
        <em>“The pacing and the vivid action scenes will
      satisfy hard-core military-SF buffs. At the same time, the
      characters and the ethical foundations under them are at the
      high level we have come to associate with Card. Laying their
      own foundations under Card’s Ender Wiggins saga, the
      Formic Wars promise to add to Card’s already high
      reputation and to his collaborator’s as well.”
      —</em>
        Booklist
        <em>,</em>
        *starred review
      </p>
      <p>
        “Card and Johnston explore human ignorance and
      compassion through a tapestry of galactic warfare in the
      second volume of the Formic Wars trilogy.... Social upheavals
      and political ineptitude are realized through rich
      characterization and brisk action.” —
        <em>Publishers Weekly</em>
      </p>
      <h3>About the Author</h3>
      <p>
        ORSON SCOTT CARD is the author of the international
      bestsellers
        <em>Shadow of the Giant</em>
        ,
        <em>Shadow Puppets</em>
        ,
        <em>Shadow of the Hegemon</em>
        , and
        <em>Ender's Shadow</em>
        , and of the beloved classic of
      science fiction
        <em>Ender's Game</em>
        , as well as the acclaimed fantasy
      series The Tales of Alvin Maker. He lives in Greensboro,
      North Carolina.
      </p>
      <p>
        AARON JOHNSTON is a
        <em>New York Times</em>
        bestselling author, comic book
      writer, and screenwriter who often collaborates with science
      fiction legend Orson Scott Card. He and his wife are the
      parents of four children.
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
