<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Shadow's Edge</title>
  <id>urn:book:da4cb3a9-dc18-473e-ac37-c58d898070c7</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:56:13Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_541.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Shadow's Edge" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_34_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Brent Weeks" />
  <link href="../../Brent%20Weeks/Shadow%27s%20Edge%20%28541%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Brent%20Weeks/Shadow%27s%20Edge%20%28541%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Brent%20Weeks/Shadow%27s%20Edge%20%28541%29/Shadow%27s%20Edge%20-%20Brent%20Weeks.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="709 KB" />
  <link href="../../Brent%20Weeks/Shadow%27s%20Edge%20%28541%29/Shadow%27s%20Edge%20-%20Brent%20Weeks.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="897 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Brent Weeks</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_34_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2008-11-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Orbit</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="Romance" />
  <category term="Adventure" />
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Night Angel Trilogy" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 2 in the Night Angel Trilogy series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">
      Kylar Stern has rejected the assassin's life. The Godking's
    successful coup has left Kylar's master, Durzo, and his best
    friend, Logan, dead. He is starting over: new city, new
    friends, and new profession.
      <br />
    </p>
    <p xmlns="">But when he learns that Logan might actually be alive and in
    hiding, Kylar is faced with an agonizing choice: will he give
    up the way of shadows forever and live in peace with his new
    family, or will he risk everything by taking on the ultimate
    hit?</p>
    <h3 xmlns="">Review</h3>
    <p xmlns="">I was mesmerized from start to finish. Unforgettable
    characters, a plot that kept me guessing, non-stop action and
    the kind of in-depth storytelling that makes me admire a
    writer's work Terry Brooks</p>
    <h3 xmlns="">About the Author</h3>
    <p xmlns="">Brent Weeks was born and raised in Montana. After graduating
    from Hillsdale College, Brent had brief stints walking the
    earth like Caine from Kung Fu and tending bar. He started
    writing on bar napkins, then on lesson plans, then full time.
    The New York Times bestselling author of the Night Angel
    Trilogy, Brent lives in Oregon with his wife, Kristi. Paul
    Boehmer appeared for two seasons at the Old Globe Theatre in
    San Diego, California, where he played Oberon/Theseus in A
    Midsummer Night's Dream and Lucius in Titus Andronicus. He also
    appeared in The Constant Wife, played Banquo in Macbeth, and
    was Antipholus of Syracuse in The Comedy of Errors in the 2005
    Summer Rep Season at the Globe. He has appeared in Sir Peter
    Halls's acclaimed Broadway production of Oscar Wilde's An Ideal
    Husband, Off-Broadway in the New York premiere of Miss Evers'
    Boys, and Off-Off-Broadway in New Yorrick, New Yorrick and End
    of the Day. He has appeared regionally at the Pioneer Theatre
    Company, Arena Stage, Seattle Rep, Huntington Theatre Company,
    Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park, Cleveland Playhouse, Missouri
    Repertory Theatre, Walnut Street Theatre, Syracuse Stage,
    Berkshire Theatre Festival, and Theatre Works Palo Alto. His
    film and television appearances include The Good German, The
    Thomas Crown Affair, Star Trek: Enterprise, Star Trek: Voyager,
    Star Trek: Deep Space Nine, Frasier, Judging Amy, Guiding
    Light, and All My Children. Paul is most proud of his
    award-winning unabridged recording of Moby Dick. He holds a BFA
    in acting from Southern Methodist University and an MFA in
    acting from the Professional Theatre Training Program at the
    University of Delaware.</p>
  </content>
</entry>
