<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>The Crystal City</title>
  <id>urn:book:a1b3d757-596e-40a4-bbaf-4602b6979812</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:28Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_403.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="The Crystal City" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Orson Scott Card" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/The%20Crystal%20City%20%28403%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/The%20Crystal%20City%20%28403%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/The%20Crystal%20City%20%28403%29/The%20Crystal%20City%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="292 KB" />
  <link href="../../Orson%20Scott%20Card/The%20Crystal%20City%20%28403%29/The%20Crystal%20City%20-%20Orson%20Scott%20Card.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="431 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>Orson Scott Card</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_19_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2003-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Tor</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Speculative Fiction" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Tales of Alvin Maker" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 6 in the Tales of Alvin Maker series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>
        Using the lore and the folk-magic of the men and women who
      settled North America, Orson Scott Card has created an
      alternate world where magic works, and where that magic has
      colored the entire history of the colonies. Charms and
      beseechings, hexes and potions, all have a place in the lives
      of the people of this world. Dowsers find water, the second
      sight warns of dangers to come, and a torch can read a
      person's future---or their heart.
        <br />
        In this world where "knacks" abound, Alvin, the seventh
      son of a seventh son, is a very special man indeed. He's a
      Maker; he has the knack of understanding how things are put
      together, how to create them, repair them, keep them whole,
      or tear them down. He can heal hearts as well as bones, he
      build a house, he can calm the waters or blow up a storm. And
      he can teach his knack to others, to the measure of their own
      talent.
        <br />
        Alvin has been trying to avert the terrible war that
      his wife, Peggy, a torch of extraordinary power, has seen
      down the life-lines of every American. Now she has sent him
      down the Mizzippy to the city of New Orleans, or Nueva
      Barcelona as they call it under Spanish occupation. Alvin
      doesn't know exactly why he's there, but when he and his
      brother-in-law, Arthur Stuart, find lodgings with a family of
      abolitionists who know Peggy, he suspects he'll find out
      soon.
        <br />
        But Nueva Barcelona is about to experience a plague,
      and Alvin's efforts to protect his friends by keeping them
      healthy will create more danger than he could ever have
      suspected. And in saving the poor people of the city, Alvin
      will be put to the greatest test of his life---a test that
      will draw on all his power. For the time has come for him to
      turn to his old friend Tenskwa-Tawa, the Red Prophet who
      controls the lands to the west of the Mizzippy. Now Alvin
      must take the first steps on the road to the Crystal City
      that was shown to him in a vision so long ago.
        <br />
      </p>
      <h3>From Publishers Weekly</h3>
      <p>
        If not the best in the series, Card's latest Alvin Maker
      novel (after 1998's Heartfire: Tales of Alvin Maker V) still
      enchants. In the author's alternative American frontier
      world, Indians work the magics of nature, Africans transform
      themselves with trinkets and whites have knacks-magical
      talents that allow them to shape metal, find water, win the
      hearts of followers and more. Alvin, the powerful seventh son
      of a seventh son, can create things that cannot be destroyed.
      He also has more than his fair share of knacks as well as
      some Indian magic. Determined to stop suffering where he
      finds it, he dreams of building the Crystal City, which will
      help mankind live in peace. A large part of the appeal lies
      in the book's homegrown characters using their powers for
      ordinary purposes. A blacksmith's knack shapes axes that
      never dull, while a midwife can sense the health of her
      patients. Even as Alvin performs miracles to lead thousands
      of slaves out of bondage, he is filled with uncertainty about
      what to do with his life and self-doubt because he couldn't
      save his stillborn child. Alvin's fans will be relieved to
      know that the City is indeed begun in this volume, but those
      who were expecting the start of the civil war, previously
      billed as forthcoming, will have longer to wait.
        <br />
        Copyright 2003 Reed Business Information, Inc.
      </p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>
        "Card creates a solid episode in what is perhaps his most
      interesting ongoing series."--Bookpage on
        <em>The Crystal City</em>
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "By mixing real settings, people, and situations with his
      own brand of characterization and biblical metaphor, the
      author has created an early America as it might have been if
      magic had played a part in its development."--Rocky Mountain
      News on
        <em>The Crystal City</em>
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "Card creates a solid episode in what is perhaps his most
      interesting ongoing series." (
        <em>Bookpage</em>
        )
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        "By mixing real settings, people, and situations with his
      own brand of characterization and biblical metaphor, the
      author has created an early America as it might have been if
      magic had played a part in its development." (
        <em>Rocky Mountain News</em>
        )
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
