<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <title>Legend</title>
  <id>urn:book:9ccdaa20-eadb-46a1-92c4-2ac89b03dd0c</id>
  <updated>2016-12-16T11:55:59Z</updated>
  <link href="./book_503.xml" type="application/atom+xml;type=entry;profile=opds-catalog" rel="self" title="Legend" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="start" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../index.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="AllSimonsBooks" />
  <link href="../authorlist/authorlist_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="Authors" />
  <link href="../author_0/author_28_Page_1.xml" type="application/atom+xml;profile=opds-catalog;kind=navigation" rel="breadcrumb" title="David Gemmell" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Legend%20%28503%29/c2o_resizedcover.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Legend%20%28503%29/c2o_thumbnail.jpg" type="image/jpg" rel="http://opds-spec.org/image/thumbnail" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Legend%20%28503%29/Legend%20-%20David%20Gemmell.epub" type="application/epub+zip" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as EPUB" displaysize="408 KB" />
  <link href="../../David%20Gemmell/Legend%20%28503%29/Legend%20-%20David%20Gemmell.mobi" type="application/x-mobipocket-ebook" rel="http://opds-spec.org/acquisition" title="Download this ebook as MOBI" displaysize="557 KB" />
  <author>
    <name>David Gemmell</name>
    <uri>../author_0/author_28_Page_1.xml</uri>
  </author>
  <published>1984-01-02T06:00:00Z</published>
  <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
  <dcterms:publisher>Del Rey</dcterms:publisher>
  <category term="Science Fiction" />
  <category term="Fantasy" />
  <category term="General" />
  <category term="Fiction" />
  <category term="Epic" />
  <category term="Good and Evil" />
  <category term="Imaginary Wars and Battles" />
  <category term="Drenai (Imaginary Place)" />
  <category term="English Fiction" />
  <category term="Fantastic Fiction; English" />
  <category term="English" />
  <category term="Fantastic Fiction" />
  <category term="Lang:en" />
  <category term="Drenai" />
  <content type="text/html">
    <p>
      <strong>Series:</strong>
      Book 1 in the Drenai series
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Summary</strong>
    </p>
    <div xmlns="">
      <p>Druss, Captain of the Axe, was the stuff of legends. But
      even as the stories grew in the telling, Druss himself grew
      older. He turned his back on his own legend and retreated to
      a mountain lair to await his old enemy, death. Meanwhile,
      barbarian hordes were on the march. Nothing could stand in
      their way. Druss reluctantly agreed to come out of
      retirement. But could even Druss live up to his own
      legends?</p>
      <h3>Review</h3>
      <p>'Has pace, conviction and gritty resolute vitality...The
      result is a book that will be enjoyed by Tolkien fans' TIMES
      EDUCATIONAL SUPPLEMENT</p>
      <h3>From the Publisher</h3>
      <p>
        David Gemmell is so committed to his work that he's
      offered to leap naked out of an airplane if it would appeal
      to readers. We haven't taken him up on the offer. However,
      David has also acknowledged that three of his major
      influences were Louis Lamour, J.R.R. Tolkien, and Stan Lee.
      Tolkien wrote back, Lamour passed away before David had any
      opportunity to contact him, and Stan Lee lived thousands of
      miles away from David's British home. One out of three wasn't
      bad, but it could be improved upon.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        We were at the San Diego ComicCon, rustling up new
      readers, and David had just finished a two-hour continuous
      signing. A friend of mine spotted a familiar face, so I
      excused myself and darted away, returning a few moments later
      to say, "David Gemmell, I'd like you to meet Stan Lee." A
      tall, ruddy, and normally poised individual, David was struck
      speechless. Here was the man who, through his Marvel Comics
      stories, had reinvented the relationship between heroes and
      villains, forever blurring the barriers between good and
      evil. Before long the two fantasists were chatting away
      happily. Stan's wife, Joan, being British, was especially
      gracious to the London-born Gemmell. And Stan quickly
      demanded an autographed copy of LEGEND.
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        David's a dynamic storyteller. His lands live and breathe.
      His heroes are mighty swordsmen, ax-wielders, and
      post-apocalyptic adventurers. In their prime they were the
      best in the business, but in David's tales, they've often
      passed their prime, so all they really want is peace and
      quiet. But life (and the author) aren't that kind, and these
      heroes are forced out of retirement, forced to face bloody
      hordes of the undead, armies from Hell. Worse, his heroes are
      generally saddled with young, green heroes. (Nothing drives
      you crazy more than a cocky kid.) But they overcome, and the
      cocky kids become heroes, too. This is great reading.
        <br />
                                                                                --Steve
      Saffel, Senior Editor
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
